<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>The blog of AWS Developer Associate</title>
 <link href="/sturdy-carnival/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/sturdy-carnival"/>
 <updated>2018-10-05T19:20:12+10:00</updated>
 <id>/sturdy-carnival</id>
 <author>
   <name>AWS Developer Associate</name>
   <email>test@example.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>VPC Summary</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/networking/2018/07/18/VPC-Summary.html"/>
   <updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/networking/2018/07/18/VPC-Summary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;nat-instances&quot;&gt;NAT Instances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When creating NAT instance, Disable Source/Destination check on instances.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NAT instance must be in a public subnet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There must be a route out of the private subnet to the NAT instance, in order for this to work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The amount of traffic that NAT instances can support depends on the instance size. If you are bottlenecking, increase the instance size.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can create high availability using Autoscaling Groups, multiple subnets in different AZ’s, and a script to automate failover.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NAT instances are always behind a security group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nat-gateways&quot;&gt;NAT Gateways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preferred by the enterprise group.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scale up automatically upto 10GBps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No need to patch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not associated with security groups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automatically assigned with a public ip address.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember to update your route tables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No need to disable Source / Destination checks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More secure than using NAT instances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;network-acls&quot;&gt;Network ACLs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your VPC automatically comes with a default ACL, and by default it allows all inbound and outbound traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can create custom network ACLs. And by default custom ACL denies all inbound and outbound traffic until you add rules.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each subnet in your VPC must be associated with a network ACL. If you dont explicitly associate a subnet with a network ACL, the subnet is automatically associated with the default network ACL.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can associate a network ACL with multiple subnets; however, a subnet can be associated with only one network ACL at a time. When you associate a network ACL with a subnet, the previous association is removed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network ACLs contain a numbered list of rules that is evaluated in order, starting with lowest numbered rule.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network ACLs have seperate inbound and outbound rules, and each rule can either allow or deny traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network ACLs are stateless, responses to allow inbound traffic are subjected to the rules for outbound traffic. (vice versa).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block IP addresses using NACLs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;application-load-balancers&quot;&gt;Application Load Balancers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will need at least 2 public subnets in order to deploy an application load balancer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vpc-flow-logs&quot;&gt;VPC Flow Logs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot enable flow logs for VPCs that are peered with your VPC unless the peer VPC is in your account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot tag a flow log.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After youve created a flow log, you cannot change the configuration; for example, you cannot associate a different IAM rule with the current flow log.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not all IP traffic is monitored
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic generated by instances when they contact Amazon DNS server. If you use your own DNS server, then all traffic to that DNS server is logged.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic generated by a Windows instance for Amazon Windows license activation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic to and from 169.254.169.254 for instance metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;DHCP traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic to the reserved IP address for the default VPC router.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>VPC</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/networking/2018/07/11/VPC.html"/>
   <updated>2018-07-11T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/networking/2018/07/11/VPC</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-vpc&quot;&gt;What is a VPC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This of a VPC as a virtual data centre in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aws-definition&quot;&gt;AWS Definition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (Amazon VPC) lets you provision a logically isolated section of the Amazon Web Services (AWS) Cloud where you can launch AWS resources in a virtual network that you define. You have complete control over your virtual networking environment, including selection of your own IP address range, creation of subnets, and configuration of route tables and network gateways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily customize the network configuration for your Amazon Virtual Private Cloud. For example, you can create a public-facing subnet  for your webservers that has access to the Internet, and place your backend systems such as databases, or application servers in a private facing subnet with no Internet access. You can leverage multiple layers of security, including security groups and network access control lists, to help control access to Amazon EC2 Instances in each subnet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally You can create Hardware Virtual Private Cloud (VPN) connection between your coorporate datacenter and your VPC and leverage the AWS cloud as an extension of your corporate datacenter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-you-do-with-vpc&quot;&gt;What can you do with VPC?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch instances into a subnet of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assign Custom IP address range in each subnet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure routing tables between subnets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create internet gateway and attach it to our VPC.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Much better security control over the AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instance security groups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subnet network access control lists (ACLS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;default-vpc-vs-custom-vpc&quot;&gt;Default VPC vs Custom VPC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Default VPC is user friendly, allowing you to immedietely deploy instances.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All Subnets in the default VPC have a route out to the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each EC2 instance has both public and private IP address.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If we deploy the instance to a private VPC subnet, the instance will not have any public IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vpc-peering&quot;&gt;VPC Peering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows you to connect one VPC with another via direct network route using private IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instances behave as if they were on the same private network.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can peer VPC’s with other AWS accounts as well as with other VPC’s in the same account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peering is in a star configuration: ie 1 central VPC peers with 4 others. &lt;strong&gt;No Transitive Peering!!&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips-vpc&quot;&gt;Exam Tips VPC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think of VPC as a logical datacenter in AWS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consists of IGWs (Or Virtual Private Gateways), Route Tables, Network Access Control Lists, Subnets, and Security Groups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Subnet = 1 Availability Zone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security Groups are Stateful; Network Access Control Lists are Stateless.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No Transitive peering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips---nat-instances&quot;&gt;Exam Tips - NAT Instances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When creating a NAT instance, Disable Source/Destination Check on the Instance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NAT instances must be in a public subnet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There must be a route out of the private subnet to the NAT instance, in order for this to work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The amount of traffic that NAT instances can support depends on the size. If you are bottlenecking, increase the instance size.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also create high availability using auto scaling groups, multiple subnets in different AZs, and a script to automate failover.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Its behind a gateway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips---nat-gateways&quot;&gt;Exam Tips - NAT Gateways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preferred by the enterprise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scale automatically upto 10Gbps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No need to patch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not associated with security groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automatically assigned a public ip address&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember to update your route tables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No need to disable Source/Destination Checks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More secure than a NAT instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips---network-acls&quot;&gt;Exam Tips - Network ACLs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your VPC automatically comes a default network ACL, and by default it allows all outbound and inbound traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can create custom network ACLs. By default, each custom network ACL denies all inbound and outbound traffic until you add rules.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each subnet in your VPC must be associated with a network ACL. If you dont explicitly associate a subnet with a network ACL, the subnet is automatically associated with the default network ACL.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can associate a network ACL with multiple subnets; however one subnet can be associated with one network ACL at a time. When you associate a network ACL with a subnet, the previous association is removed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network ACLs contain a numbered list of rules that is evaluated in order, starting with the lowest numbered rule.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network ACLs have seperate inbound and outbound rules, and each rule can either allow or deny traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network ACLs are stateless; reponses to allowed inbound traffic are subject to the rules for outbound traffic (and vice versa).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block IP Addresses using ACLs not security groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vpc-flow-logs&quot;&gt;VPC Flow Logs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPC Flow logs is a feature that enables you to capture information about the IP traffic going to and from network interfaces in your VPC. Flow log data is stored using Amazon CloudWatch Logs. After youve created flow log, you can view and retrieve its data in Amazon CloudWatch Logs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flow logs can be created at 3 levels
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;VPC&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Subnet&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Network Interface Level&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips---vpc-flow-logs&quot;&gt;Exam Tips - VPC Flow Logs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot enable flow logs for VPCs that are peered with your VPC unless the peer VPC is in your account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot tag a flow log.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After you have created a flow log, you cannot change its configuration; for example, you can’t associate a different IAM role with the flow log.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not all IP traffic is monitored.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic generated by instances when they contact the Amazon DNS server. If you use your own DNS server, then all traffic to that DNS server is logged.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic generated by a Windows instance for Amazon Windows license activation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic to and from 169.254.169.254 for instance metadata&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;DHCP traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Traffic to the reserved IP address for the default VPC router.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nat-vs-bastion&quot;&gt;NAT vs Bastion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A NAT instance is used to provide internet traffic to ec2 instances in private subnets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Bastion is used to securely administer EC2 instances ( using SSH or RDP ) in private subnets. In Australia we call them jump boxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Route53 - Routing Policies</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/2018/06/25/Route53-Routing-Policies.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-25T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/2018/06/25/Route53---Routing-Policies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;types-of-routing-policies&quot;&gt;Types of Routing Policies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weighted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Latency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Failover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geolocation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;Simple&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the default routing policy when you create a new record set. This is most commonly used when you have a single resource that performs a given function for your domain, for example, one web server that serves content for the http://acloud.guru website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weighted&quot;&gt;Weighted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows you to split your traffic based on different weights assigned. For example you can set 10% of your traffic to go to US-EAST-1 and 90% of your traffic to go to EU-WEST-1. This doesnt do it by request, it does via the length of the day. Usually used for testing your new website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;latency&quot;&gt;Latency&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latency based routing allows you to route your traffic based on the lowest network latency for your end user. ( ie which region will give them the fastest response time). To use latency-based routing you create a latency resource record set for the Amazon EC2 ( or ELB ) resource in each region that hosts your website. When Amazon Route 53 receives a query for your site, it selects the latency resource record set for the region that gives the user the lowest latency. Route53 then responds with the value associated with that resource set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;failover&quot;&gt;Failover&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failover routing policies are used when you want to create an active/passive setup. For example you may want your primary site to be in EU-WEST-2 and your secondary DR Site in AP-SOUTHEAST-2. Route53 will monitor the health of your primary site using a health check. A health check monitors the health of your endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;geolocation&quot;&gt;Geolocation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allows you to direct your traffic to different routes based on the geographic location of your users. ( location from which the DNS queries originate from ). For example, you might want all queries from Europe to be routed to a fleet of EC2 instances that are specifically configured for your European customers. These servers may have the local language of your European customers and all prices are displayed in Euros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dns-exam-tips&quot;&gt;DNS Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elastic Load Balancers never have an ipv4 address.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand the difference between an Alias Record and a CNAME.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If youre ever given the choice, always choose an Alias Record over a CNAME, because it dosent cost money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember the different routing polices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DNS 101</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/networking/2018/06/24/DNS-101.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-24T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/networking/2018/06/24/DNS-101</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DNS is used to convert human friendly names, such as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://google.com&lt;/code&gt; into an Internet Protocol Address such as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://92.93.94.95&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IP addresses are used by computers to identify each other on the network. IP addresses commonly come in 2 different forms, IPv4 and IPv6.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IPv4 address space is a 32 bit field and has over 4 billion different addresses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IPv6 address space is a 128 bit field and has over 340 undecillion addresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-level-domains&quot;&gt;Top Level Domains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The last word in a domain name represents the “top level domain”.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.com&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.edu&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.gov&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.me&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.io&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.org&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The second word in a domain name represents the second level domain name” &lt;em&gt;optional and depends on the domain.&lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;co&lt;/strong&gt;.uk&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;gov&lt;/strong&gt;.uk&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;com&lt;/strong&gt;.au&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;domain-registrars&quot;&gt;Domain Registrars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A registrar is an authority that can assign domain names directly under one or more top-level domains. These domains are registered with InterNIC, a service of ICANN, which enforces uniqueness of domain names across the Internet. Each domain name becomes registered in a central database known as the WhoIS database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soa-records&quot;&gt;SOA Records&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Of Authrority Records&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The SOA Record Stores Information About&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The name of the server that supplied the data for the zone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The administrator of the zone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The current version of the zone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The number of seconds a secondary name server should wait before checking for updates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The number of seconds a secondary name server should wait before retrying a failed zone transfer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The maximum number of seconds that a secondary name server can use data before it must either be refreshed or expire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The default number of seconds for the time-to-live file on resource records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ns-records&quot;&gt;NS Records&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NS stands for Name Server Records.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Used by Top Level Domain servers to direct traffic to Content DNS server which contains authoritative DNS records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-records&quot;&gt;A Records&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The A record is the fundemental type of DNS record and the “A” in A record stands for “Address”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The A record is used by a computer to translate the name of the domain to the IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Elastic load balancers never have an IPv4 / IPv6 Address, they always have a DNS name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ttl-record&quot;&gt;TTL Record&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The length that a DNS record is cached on either the Resolving Server or the users own local PC is equal to the value of the “Time To Live” (TTL) in seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The lower the time to live, the faster changes to DNS records take to propagate through the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When migrating to different servers, always remember to lower the TTL to 300 seconds ( 5 minutes ) since 2 days before the migration, since by default the TTL is set to 2 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cnames&quot;&gt;CNAMES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Canonical Name ( CName ) can be used to resolve one domain name to another.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For example, you may have a mobile website with the domain name http://m.acloud.guru that is used for when users browse to your domain name on their mobile devices. You may also want the name http://mobile.acloud.guru to resolve this same address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alias-records&quot;&gt;Alias Records&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alias Records are used to map resource record sets in your hosted zone to Elastic Load Balancers, CloudFront distributions, or S3 buckets that are configured as websites.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alias Records work like CNAME record in that you can map one DNS name (www.example.com) to another &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;target&lt;/code&gt; DNS name (elb1234.elb.amazonaws.com).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Key difference - A CNAME cant be used for naked domain names (zone apex record)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cant have a CNAME for http://acloud.guru, it must be either an A record or an Alias.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alias resource record sets can save you time because Amazon Route53 automatically recognizes changes in the record sets that the alias resource record set refers to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ELB’s do not have a predefined public IPv4 addresses, you resolve them using a DNS name.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand the difference between as Alias Record and a CNAME.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Given the choice always choose an Alias Record over a CNAME.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CloudFormation</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/2018/06/23/CloudFormation.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-23T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/2018/06/23/CloudFormation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-cloudformation-&quot;&gt;What is CloudFormation ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most powerful parts of AWS, CloudFormation allows you to take what was once traditional hardware infrastructure and convert it into code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CloudFormation gives developers and system administrators an way to create and manage a collection of related AWS resources, provisioning and updating them in an orderly and predictable fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You dont need to figure out the order for provisioning AWS services or the subtleties of making those dependencies work. CloudFormation takes care of this for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the AWS resources are deployed, you can modify and update them in a controlled and prdictable way, in effect &lt;strong&gt;applying version control to your AWS infrastructure the same way you do with your software.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Cloud Formation Template&lt;/strong&gt; is essentially an architectural diagram and a &lt;strong&gt;Cloud Formation Stack&lt;/strong&gt; is the end result of that diagram (i.e. what is actually provisioned ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You create, update, and delete a collection of resources by creating, updating, and deleting stacks using CloudFormation templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CloudFormation templates are in &lt;strong&gt;JSON&lt;/strong&gt; format or &lt;strong&gt;YAML&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;elements-of-a-template&quot;&gt;Elements of a template&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory Elements&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;List of AWS Resources and their associated configuration values.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional Elements
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The template’s file format &amp;amp; version number&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Template Parameters
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;The input values that are supplied at stack creation time. Limit of 60.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Output values
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The output values required once a stack has finished building ( such as the Public IP address, ELB address, etc) Limit of 60.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List of data tables
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use to look up static configuration values such as AMI’s etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple-template&quot;&gt;Simple Template&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JSON&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Resources&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;HelloBucket&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;AWS::S3::Bucket&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YAML&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-yaml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;HelloBucket&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;AWS::S3::Bucket&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outputting-data&quot;&gt;Outputting Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can use Fn:GetAtt to output data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;PublicIP&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Description&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Public IP address of the web server&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Value&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Fn::GetAtt&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;WebServerHost&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;PublicIp&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default the &lt;em&gt;“automatic rollback on error”&lt;/em&gt; ferature is &lt;strong&gt;ENABLED&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are &lt;strong&gt;CHARGED&lt;/strong&gt; for errors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CloudFormation is free.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stacks can wait for applications to be provisioned using the &lt;em&gt;“WaitCondition”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use the function &lt;em&gt;Fn:GetAtt&lt;/em&gt; to output data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Route53 completely supported. This includes creating &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; hosted zones or &lt;em&gt;updating&lt;/em&gt; existing ones.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can create A Records, Aliases etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;IAM Role Creation and Assignment is also supported.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If customer is new to AWS use ElasticBeanstalk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If customer wants to convert their infrastructure into code, use CloudFormation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Simple Workflow Service</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/workflow/2018/06/22/Simple-Workflow-Service.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/workflow/2018/06/22/Simple-Workflow-Service</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Amazon Simple Workflow Service (Amazon SWF) is a web service that makes it easy to coordinate work across distributed application components. Amazon SWF enables applications for a range of use cases, including media processing, web application back-ends, business process workflows, and analytics pipelines, to be designed as a coordination of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks represent invocations of various processing steps in an application which can be performed by executable code, web service calls, human actions, and scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worker are programs that interact with amazon SWF to get tasks.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Process received tasks and return results.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A decider is a program that controls the coordination of tasks, ie: their ordering, concurrency, and scheduling according to the application logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workers can run on EC2 instances or on machines behind firewalls. Amazon SWF brokers the interactions between workers and deciders. Allows deciders to get consistent views into the progress of tasks and to initiate new tasks in an ongoing manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same Amazon SWF stores tasks, assigns them to workers when are ready, and monitors their progress. &lt;strong&gt;It ensures that a task is assigned only once and is never duplicated.&lt;/strong&gt; Since Amazon SWF maintains the applications state durably, workers and deciders dont have to keep track of execution state. They can run independently, and scale quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All your SWF activities are all scoped into a domain. Domains Isolate a set of types, execution, and tasks list from others within the same account.
&lt;em&gt;You can register a domain by using the AWS Management Console or by using the RegisterDomain action in the Amazon SWF API.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Parameters are defined in JSON&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Workflow can be 1 year and the value is measured in seconds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;swf-vs-sqs&quot;&gt;SWF vs SQS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon SWF presents a task-oriented API, whereas Amazon SQS offers a message-oriented API.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SWF ensures task is executed only once, where as SQS you have to handle duplicated messages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SWF keeps track of all the tasks and events in an application, whereas SQS you have to keep track of all the tasks and events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Simple Queue Service</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/Simple-Queue-Service.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/Simple-Queue-Service</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Amazon SQS is a web service that gives you access to a message queue that can be used to store messages while waiting for a computer to process them. Amazon SQS is a distributed queue system that enables web service applications to quickly and reliably queue messages that one component in the application generates to be consumed by another component. A queue is a temporary repository for messages that are awaiting processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using amazon SQS, you can decouple the components of an application so they run independently, with Amazon SQS easing message management between components. Any component of a distributed application can store messages in a fail-safe queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messages can contain upto 256KB of text in any format. Any component can later retrieve the messages programmatically using the Amazon SQS API. The queue act as a buffer between the component producing and saving data, and the component receiving the data for processing. This means the queue resolves issues that arise if the producer is producing work faster than the consumer can process it, or if the producer or consumer are only intermittently connected to the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon SQS ensures delivery of each message at least once, and supports multiple readers and writers interacting with the same queue. A single queue can be used simultaneously by many distributed application components, with no need for those components to coordinate with each other to share the queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon SQS is engineered to always be available and deliver messages. One of the resulting tradeoffs is that SQS does not guarantee first in, first out delivery of messages. For many distributed applications, each message can stand on its own, and as long as all messages are delivered, the order is not important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your system requires that the order be preserved, you can place sequencing information in each message, so that you can reorder the messages when the queue returns them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have a number of images which needs to be encoded, In an amazon SQS worker queue, you can create an SQS message for each file specifying the command (jpeg-encode) and the location of the file in amazon s3. A pool of EC2 instances running the needed image processing software does the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asynchonously pull the task messages from the queue. ( polling from the queue ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retrieves the named file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Processes the conversion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writes the image back to S3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writes the “task-complete” message to another queue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deletes the original task message.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checks for more messages in the working queue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can enable auto scaling depending on the size of the queue. More messages in the queue, more ec2 instances you spin up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does not offer FIFO.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12 hours visibility timeout.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will deliver messages at least once, most of the time it does deliver your messages exactly once. Design your applications so that even if it did deliver the message more than once, it doesnt create errors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;256KB message sizes now available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Billed at 64KB chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;256 KB messages will be billed at 64 x 4.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First 1 million amazon SQS requests are free.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$0.50 per 1 million Amazon SQS Requests per month thereafter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A single request can have from 1 to 10 messages, up to a maximum total payload of 256KB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Simple Notification Service</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/Simple-Notification-Service.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/Simple-Notification-Service</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web service that makes it easy to setup, operate, and send notifications from the cloud.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provides developers with a highly scaleable, flexible and cost effective capability to publish messages from an application and immedietely deliver them to the subscribers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follows the “pub-sub” paradigm - using a “push” mechanism. &lt;em&gt;no need for polling&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay as you go pricing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email &amp;amp; SMS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push notifications to Apple, Google, FireOS, and Windows Devices, as well as Android Devices with Baidu Cloud Push.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQS and any HTTP endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stored in multiple availability zones. - prevents messages being lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows you to group multiple recipients using topics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One topic can support deliveries to multiple endpoints ( Will be formatted Appropriately )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;iOS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Android&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SMS&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instantaneous, Pushbased Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple API’s and easy integration with applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flexible message delivery over multiple transport protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inexpensive, pay-as-you-go model with no up-front costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web-based AWS Management Console offers the simplicity of a point-and-click interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sns-vs-sqs&quot;&gt;SNS vs SQS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both messaging services in AWS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SNS - Push&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQS - Pull ( Polls )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing&quot;&gt;Pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$0.50 per 1 million SNS Requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$0.06 per 100,000 Notification Deliveries over HTTP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$0.75 per 100 Notification deliveries over SMS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$2.00 per 100,000 Notification deliveries over Email
&lt;em&gt;Number of requests + delivery mechanism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;SNS dataype = JSON&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SQS Summary</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/SQS-Summary.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/SQS-Summary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQS messages can be delivered multiple times and in any order.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Default visibility is 30 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum timeout is 12 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you wish to extend the message visibility since the timeout is not enough to fully process and delete the message, you can use &lt;strong&gt;Change Message Visibility&lt;/strong&gt; action to specify a new timeout value. Amazon SQS restarts the timeout period using the new value.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQS long polling dosent return a response until a message arrives in the queue, or the long poll times out. SQS long polling makes it easy and inexpensive to retrieve messages from your SQS queue as soon as they are available. &lt;em&gt;Maximum long poll timeout = 20 seconds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;example-question&quot;&gt;Example Question&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polling in a tight loops is burning CPU cycles and costing the company money. How could you fix this?
&lt;strong&gt;Enable long polling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fanning-out-sqs&quot;&gt;Fanning out SQS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create an SNS topic in SNS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create and subscribe multiple SQS queues to the SNS topic.
When ever a message is sent to the SNS topic, the message will be fanned out to the SQS queues. SNS will deliver the message to all the SQS queues that are subsribed to the topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SNS Summary</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/SNS-Summary.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/messaging/2018/06/22/SNS-Summary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instantaneous, push-based delivery (polling)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protocols include
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HTTP&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HTTPS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email JSON&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Amazon SQS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Application&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Messages can be customized for each protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Elastic Beanstalk</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/loadbalancer/2018/06/22/Elastic-Beanstalk.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/loadbalancer/2018/06/22/Elastic-Beanstalk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deploy, monitor and scale applications quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provides developers or end users with the ability to provision application infrastructure in an almost transparent manner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gui for AWS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highly abstract focus towards infrastructure, focusing on components and performance - not configuration and specifications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Significantly simplify infrastructure management, allowing applications to be deployed into infrastructure environments easily.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Primarily aimed at beginners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-architecture-components&quot;&gt;Key Architecture Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications are high level structure in beanstalk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Either your entier application, is one EB application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each logical component of your application can be an EB application or a EB environment within an application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications can have multiple environments ( Prod, Staging, Dev, V1, V2, V1.1 or functional type [ backend, frontend] )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Environments are either single instances or scalable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Environments are either web server environments or worker environments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application versions are unique packages which represent versions of apps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An application is uploaded to Elastic beanstalk as a application bundle - .zip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each ‘application’ can have many different versions 1:M relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application versions can be deployed to environments within an Application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-configurations-options&quot;&gt;Key configurations options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.NET&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Java&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nodejs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can do both application level updates, as well as configuration level updates. These can be rolling updates, all at once, one instance at a time, also do them by a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elastic Beanstalk is a free service. But the services you provision from elastic beanstalk, the pricing depends on what you provision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can have multiple versions of your application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You appplications can be split into tiers ( Web Tier / Application Tier / Database Tier ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can update your application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can update the configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updates can be 1 instance at a time, a % of instances or an immutable update.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You pay for the resources that you use, but elastic beanstalk is free.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If elastic beanstalk creates your RDS database then it will delete it when you delete your application. If not then the RDS instance stays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Languages supported
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Apache Tomcat for Java applications&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Apache HTTP Server for PHP applications&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Apacahe HTTP Server for Python applications&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nginx or Apache HTTP Server for Nodejs applications&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Passenger or Puma for Ruby applications&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Microsoft IIS, 7.5, 8.0, and 8.5 for .NET applications.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Java SE&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Go&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DynamoDB Summary</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/22/DynamoDB-Summary.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/22/DynamoDB-Summary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-dynamodb&quot;&gt;What is dynamoDB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast and flexible NOSQL database service for all application that need consistent, single digit millisecond latency at any scale. It is a fully managed database and supports both document and key-value data models. Its flexible data model and reliable performance make it a great fit for mobile, web, gaming, ad-tech, IoT and many other applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-facts&quot;&gt;Quick Facts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stored on SSD Storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread Across 3 geographically distinct data centres.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventaul Consistent Reads (Default)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consistency across all copies of data is usually reached within a second. Repeating a read after a short time should return the updated data. (Best read performance).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strong Consistent Reads
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A strongly consistent read returns a result that reflects all writes that received a successful response prior to the read.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;basics&quot;&gt;Basics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Tables
* Items ( Data in table )
* Attributes ( Column names in a table )
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;primary-keys&quot;&gt;Primary Keys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two types of primary keys available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Single Attribute (Unique ID)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Partition Key (Hash key) composed of one attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Composite (Think unique ID and a date range)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Partition Key &amp;amp; Sort Key (Hash &amp;amp; Range) composed of two attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partition Key&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;DynamoDB uses the partition key’s value as input to an internal hash function. The output from the hash function determines the partition ( this is simply the physical location in which the data is stored).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No two items in a table can have the same partition key value!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partition Key and Sort Key&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;DynamoDB uses the partition key’s value as an input to an internal hash function. The output from the hash function determines the partition ( this is simply the physical location in which the data is stored).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Two items can have the same parition key, but they &lt;strong&gt;must have a different sort key.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All items with the same partition key will be stored together but ordered using the sort key value.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;indexes&quot;&gt;Indexes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Secondary Index&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has the SAME parition key, different sort key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can ONLY be created when creating a table. They cannot be removed or modified later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Secondary Index&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has a DIFFERENT partition key and DIFFERENT sort key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be created at table creation or added LATER.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dynamodb-streams&quot;&gt;DynamoDB Streams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Used to capture any kind of modification to the DynamoDB tables.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a new item is added to the table, the stream captures an image of the entire item, including all of its attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If an item is updated, the stream captures the “before” and “after” image of any attributes that were modified in the item.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If an item is deleted from the table, the stream captures an image of the entire item before it was deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;query--scans&quot;&gt;Query &amp;amp; Scans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Query operation finds items in a table using only primary key attribute values. You must provide a partition key attribute name and a distint value to search for.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Scan operation examines every item in the table. By default,  a Scan returns all of the data attributes for every item; however you can use the &lt;strong&gt;ProjectionExpression&lt;/strong&gt; parameter so that the Scan only returns some of the attributes, rather than all of them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try to use a Query operation rather than a Scan operation as it is more efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dynamodb-provisioned-throughput-calculation&quot;&gt;DynamoDB Provisioned Throughput Calculation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read 13 items of 17 KB per second (using eventual consistency)
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;17KB to the nearest 4KB = 20&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;20KB / 4KB = 5 read units per item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;5 x 13 read items per second = 65&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;65 / 2 for eventual consistency = 32.5 (33)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;33 units of read throughput&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write 94 items of 3KB per second
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3KB to the nearest 1KB = 3&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3KB/1KB = 3 write units per item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3 x 94 write items per second = 282&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;282 / 1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;282 units of write throughput capacity&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Error code
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;400 HTTP ProvisionedThroughputExceededException&lt;/strong&gt; - You have exceeded your maximum allowed provisioned throughput for a table or for one or more global secondary indexes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps-taken-to-authenticate-with-web-identity-provider&quot;&gt;Steps taken to authenticate with Web Identity Provider&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User authenticates with Web identity Provider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They are passed a Token by their ID Provider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your code calls &lt;strong&gt;AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity&lt;/strong&gt; API and provides the providers token and specifies the ARN for the IAM Role.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;App can now access DynamoDB from between 15 minutes to 1 hour (default 1 hour).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conditional-write&quot;&gt;Conditional Write&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a price equals &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; then update the price to &lt;strong&gt;Y&lt;/strong&gt;. If the price is not equal to &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; operation fails. This is an &lt;strong&gt;Idempotent&lt;/strong&gt; operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;atomic-counters&quot;&gt;Atomic Counters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increment or Decrement a value on an existing attirbute, regardless of its value. This is not an Idempotent operation. May over-count or under-count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use conditional writes for critical stuff, atomic counters for non critical stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;batch-operations&quot;&gt;Batch Operations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BatchGetItem&lt;/strong&gt; can contain upto 1MB of data and upto 100 items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can retrieve items from multiple tables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THE FAQ OF DYNAMODB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DynamoDB - Other Key Facts</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/22/DynamoDB-Other-Key-Facts.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/22/DynamoDB---Other-Key-Facts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;conditional-writes&quot;&gt;Conditional Writes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example Scenario&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if two clients were to update a piece of data at the same time, the updates may happen at 2 different facilities, and may create unexpected outcome. In order to prevent this use, conditional writes. Lets say you want to update a price of an item, but you only want to update if its $6. So the first user do UpdateItem if Price is $6 to $15. The Price will change, the second user will also try and do a UpdateItem if Price is $6, but this time the price is 15 and the operation will fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These conditional writes are idempotent. This means that you can send the same conditional write request multiple times, but will have no further effect on the item after the first successful update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;DynamoDB support atomic counters, where you use the UpdateItem operation to increment or decrement the value of an existing attribute without interfering with other write requests. (All write requests are applied in the order in which they were recieved). For example, a web application might want to maintain a counter per visitor to their site. In this case, the application would need to increment this counter regardless of its current value.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Atomic counter updates are not idempotent. This means the counter will increment each time you call UpdateItem. If you suspect that a previous request was unsuccessful, your application could retry the UpdateItem operation; however this would risk updating the counter twice. This might be acceptable for a web site counter, because you can tolerate with slightly over-or under-counting the visitors. However in a banking application, it would be safer to use a conditional update rather than an atomic counter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the exam you will be asked if you should use the atomic counter or the conditional update, it depends if the data is critical, example voting or banking you would use conditional writes. Where as for website visitor counters you would use atomic counters.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your application needs to read multiple items, you can use the BatchGetItem API. A single &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BatchGetItem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; request can retrieve up to 1 MB of data, which can contain as many as 100 items. In addition, a single BatchGetItem request can retrieve items from multiple tables.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Web Identity Providers</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/21/Web-Identity-Providers.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-21T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/21/Web-Identity-Providers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-identity-providers&quot;&gt;Web Identity Providers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can authenticate users using &lt;strong&gt;Web Identity Providers&lt;/strong&gt; ( such as Facebook, Google, Amazon, or any other Open-ID Connect-compatible Identity provider). This is done using AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to create a role first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User Authenticates With WebIDProvider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WebIDProvider gives you a Web Identity Token.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do the AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity Request to AWS SecurityTokenService (STS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AWS (STS) gives back Temporary Security Credentials ( Defaults 1 hour )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access Key ID, Secret Access Key, Session Token.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Expiration ( Time limit )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;AssumeRoleID&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SubjectFromWebIdentityToken ( The unique ID that appears in an IAM policy variable for this particular identity provider )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using these credentials, you can access dynamodb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;steps-taken-to-authenticate&quot;&gt;Steps taken to authenticate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User Authenticates with the ID provider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They are passed a Token by their ID provider.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your code calls &lt;strong&gt;AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity&lt;/strong&gt; API and provides the providers token and specifies the ARN for the IAM Role.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;App can now access DynamoDB from between 15 minutes to 1 hour (default is 1 hour)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DynamoDB Provisioned Throughput Calculations</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/21/DynamoDB-Provisioned-Throughput-Calculations.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-21T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/21/DynamoDB-Provisioned-Throughput-Calculations</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;provisioned-throughput&quot;&gt;Provisioned Throughput&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unit of Read provisioned throughput
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All reads are rounded up to increments of 4KB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eventually Consistent Reads (default) consist of 2 reads per second.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strongly Consistent Reads consist of 1 read per second.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unit of Write provisioned throughput.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All writes are 1 KB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All writes consist of 1 write per second&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-magic-formula&quot;&gt;The magic formula&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt; - you have an application that requires to read 10 items of 1KB per second using eventual consistency. What should you set the read throughput to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Size of Read rounded to nearest 4KB chunk / 4KB) x no of items = read throughput&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Divide by 2 if eventually consistent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;* First we calculate how many read units per item we need.

* 1KB rounded to the nearest 4KB increment = 4KB
* 4KB / 4KB = 1 read unit per item.

* 1 x 10 read items = 10
* Using eventual consistency we get 10 / 2 = 5
* 5 units of read throughput
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have an application that requires to read 10 items of 6 KB per second using eventual consistency. What should you set the read throughput to?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;6 KB rounded to the nearest 4KB increment = 8KB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;8KB / 4KB = 2 read unit per item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2 x 10 read items = 20&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using eventual consistency we get 20 / 2 = 10&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10 units of read throughput&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have an application that requires to read 5 items of 10KB per second using eventual consistency. What should you set the read throughput to?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10KB rounded to the nearest 4KB increment = 12KB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;12KB / 4KB = 3 read units per item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3 x 5 read items = 15&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;using eventual consistency we get 15 / 2 = 7.5 (8) &amp;lt;- since read throughput can only be integer.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;8 units of read throughput.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have an application that requires to read 5 items of 10KB per second using **&lt;em&gt;strong consistency&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. What should you set the read throughput to?**
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10KB rounded to the nearest 4KB increment = 12KB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;12KB / 4KB = 3 read units per item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3 x 5 read items = 15&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Since we are using strong consistency 15 x 1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;15 units of read throughput&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have an application that requires to write 5 items, with each item being 10KB in size. What should the write throughput be set to?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10 KB rounded to the nearest 1KB = 10KB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10 KB / 1 KB = 10 write units per item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10 x 5 write items = 50&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;50 units of write throughput&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have an application that requires to write 12 items, with each item being 100KB in size. What should the write throughput be set to?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100 KB rounded to the nearest 1KB = 100KB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100 KB / 1 KB = 100 write units per item&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100 x 12 write items = 1200&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1200 units of write throughput&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;error-codes&quot;&gt;Error Codes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;400 HTTP Status Code &lt;strong&gt;ProvisionedThroughputExceededException&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You have exceeded the maximum allowed provisioned throughput for a table or for one or global secondary indexes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Scan vs Query API Calls</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/15/Scan-vs-Query-API-Calls.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-15T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/15/Scan-vs-Query-API-Calls</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-query&quot;&gt;What is a query&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Query operation finds items in a table using only primary key attributes values. You must provide a partition attribute name and a distinct value to search for.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can optionally provide a sort key attribute name and value, and use a comparison operator to refine the search results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default, a query returns all of the data attributes for items with the specified primary key(s); however, you can use the &lt;strong&gt;ProjectionExpression&lt;/strong&gt; parameter so that the Query only returns some of the attributes, rather than all of them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Query results are always sorted by the sort key. If the data type of the sort key is a number, the results are returned in numeric order; otherwise the results are returned in order of ASCII character code values. By default, the sort order is ascending. To reverse the order, set the &lt;strong&gt;ScanIndexForward&lt;/strong&gt; parameter to false.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default all queries are eventually consistent but can be changed to be strongly consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-scan-&quot;&gt;What is a Scan ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Scan operation examines every item in the table ( basically a table dump ). By default the scan returns all of the data attributes for every item; however, you can use the &lt;strong&gt;ProjectionExpression&lt;/strong&gt; parameter so that the Scan returns only some of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-should-i-use-a-query-or-a-scan&quot;&gt;What Should I use, a query or a Scan?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, a Query Operation is more efficient than a Scan operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Scan operation always scans the entire table, then filters out values to provide the desired result, essentially adding the extra step of removing data from the result set. Avoid using a Scan operation on a large table with a filter that removes many results, if possible. Also, as a table grows, the Scan operation slows. The Scan operation examines every item for the requested values, and can use up the provisioned throughput for a large table in a single operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For quicker response times, design your tables in a way that can use the Query, &lt;em&gt;Get&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;BatchGetItem&lt;/em&gt; APIs instead. Alternatively, design your application to use Scan operations in a way that minimizes the impact on your tables request rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Query operation finds the items in a table using only primary key attribute values. You must provide a partition key attribute name and a distinct value to search for.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Scan operation examines every item in the table. By default, a Scan returns all of the data attributes for every item; however, you can use the &lt;strong&gt;ProjectionExpression&lt;/strong&gt; parameter so that the Scan only returns some of the attributes, rather than all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Query results are always sorted by the sort key in ascending order. Set &lt;strong&gt;ScanIndexForward&lt;/strong&gt; parameter to false to reverse it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try use a Query operation than a scan operation as it is more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DynamoDB Indexes</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/15/DynamoDB-Indexes.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-15T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/15/DynamoDB-Indexes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;primary-key&quot;&gt;Primary Key&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two types of primary keys available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Attribute (unique ID)&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Partition Key (Hash Key) composed of one attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Composite (unique ID and another attribute eg: DateRange)&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Partition Key &amp;amp; Sort Key ( Hash &amp;amp; Range ) composed of two attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;partition-key&quot;&gt;Partition Key&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DynamoDB uses the partition keys value as input to an internal hash function. The output from the hash function determines the partition ( The physical location where the data will be stored. )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No two items can have the same partition key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;partition-key--sort-key&quot;&gt;Partition Key &amp;amp; Sort Key&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DynamoDB uses the partition keys value as input to the internal hash function. The output determines the physical location just like the previous definition.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two items can have the same partition key, but the sort key must be different.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All items with the same partition key will be stored together in sorted order by the sort key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;local-secondary-index&quot;&gt;Local Secondary Index&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has the partition key, different sort key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can &lt;strong&gt;only be created when you create the table.&lt;/strong&gt; They cannot be removed / modified later either.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;global-secondary-index&quot;&gt;Global Secondary Index&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has a different partition key and a different sort key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be created when your creating the table, and it can be created or added later as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dynamodb-streams&quot;&gt;DynamoDB Streams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used to capture any kind of modification to the DynamoDB tables.
    * If a new item is added to the table, the stream captures an image of the entire item. including all of its attributes.
    * If an item is updated, stream captures the “before” and “after” image of any attributes that were modified in the item.
    * If an item is deleted from the table, the stream captures an image of the entire item before it was deleted.
    * If a new user signed up to your website, it creates a new entry in the user table, this will create a stream if you have streams enabled in your dynamo table. You can use the stream to &lt;strong&gt;trigger&lt;/strong&gt; lambdas to update a dynamodb table in another region or send a welcome message to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can export data to csv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can also enable cloudwatch to trigger alarms for different different metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can have upto 5 local secondry indexes (LSI) and 5 global secondary indexes (GSI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Snowball</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/14/Snowball.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-14T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/14/Snowball</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;AWS Import/Export Disk accelerates moving large amounts data into and out of the AWS cloud using portable storage devices for transport. AWS Import/Export Disk transfers your data directly onto and off of storage devices using Amazon’s high-speed internal network and bypassing the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;types-of-snowballs&quot;&gt;Types of Snowballs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowball&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowball Edge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowmobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snowball&quot;&gt;Snowball&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snowball is petabyte-scale data transport solution that uses secure appliances to transfer large amounts of data into and out of AWS. Using Snowball addresses common challenges with large-scale data transfers including high network costs, long transfer times, and security concerns. Transferring data with Snowball is simple, fast, secure, and can be as little as one-fifth the cost of high-speed internet. 80 TB snowball in all regions. Snowball uses multiple layers of security designed to protect your data including tamper-resistent enclosures, 256-bit encryption, and an industry standard Trusted Platform Module (TPM) designed to ensure both security and full chain-of-custody of your data. Once the data transfer job has been processed and verified, AWS performs a software erasure of Snowball appliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snowball-edge&quot;&gt;Snowball Edge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS Snowball Edge is a 100TB data transfer device with on-board storage and compute capabilities. You can use Snowball Edge to move large amounts of data into and out of AWS, as a temporary storage tier for large local datasets, or to support local workloads in remote or offline locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snowball Edge connects your existing applications and infrastructure using standard storage interfaces, streamlinning the data transfer process and minimizing setup and integration. Snowball Edge can cluster together to form a local storage tier and process your data on-premises, helping ensure your applications continue to run even when they are not able to access the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Its not just storage capacity its compute capacity in a box as well&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snowmobile&quot;&gt;Snowmobile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS Snowmobile is an Exabyte-scale data transfer service use to move extremely large amounts of data to AWS. You can transfer upto 100PB per Snowmobile. a 45-long ruggedized shipping container, pulled by a semi-trailer truck. Snowmobile makes it easy to move massive volumes of data to the cloud, including video libraries, image repositories, or even complete data center migration. Transfering data with Snowmobile is secure, fast and cost effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand what snowball is&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand what Import Export is&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowball Can do
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Import to S3&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Export from S3&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Transfer Acceleration</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/14/S3-Transfer-Acceleration.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-14T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/14/S3-Transfer-Acceleration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;S3 Transfer Acceleration utilises the CloudFront Edge Network to accelerate your uploads to S3. Instead of uploading directly to your S3 bucket, you can use a distinct URL to upload directly to an edge location which will then transfer that to S3. You will get a distinct URL to upload to.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Storage Summary</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/14/S3-Storage-Summary.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-14T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/14/S3-Storage-Summary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;s3---exam-tips&quot;&gt;S3 - Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 is an Object based storage, its a place where you upload and download files.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You cannot run an os, or run a database off of S3.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Files can be of size 0 bytes all the way to 5TB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is unlimited storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Files are stored in Buckets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 is a universal namespace, all bucket names shall be unique globally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 bucket names are like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://s3-[region].amazonaws.com/[bucketname]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read after Write Consistency for PUTS of new objects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventual Consistencry for Overwrite PUTS and DELETES. ( takes some time to propergate )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 Storage Classes / Tiers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Standard S3
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;reliability of 99.999999999%&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;availability of 99.99%&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Immedietly available and frequently accessed&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;S3 Infrequent Access ( IA )
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;availablity of 99.99%&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;reliability of 99.999999999%&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Immedietly available infrequently accessed.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Charged for retreval&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;S3 Reduced Redundency
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;reliability and availability of 99.99%&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Used for reproducable content ( such as thumbnails etc ).&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Glacier
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Archived data, where you have to wait 3 - 5 hour waiting period.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Core fundementals of S3
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Key ( name )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Value ( data )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version ID&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Metadata ( data about data )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access control lists&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Object based stroage only ( flat files )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 versioning
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stores all versions of an object ( including all writes and even if you delete an object )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great backup tool&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You pay for storage for all the versions of the object.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Once enabled versioning cannot be disabled, it can only be suspended.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Integrates with lifecycle rules.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Versionings MFA Delete capability, which uses multi-factor authentication, can be used to provide an additional layer of security.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cross region replication requires versioning enabled on both the source bucket and destination bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lifecycle Management
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can be used in conjunction with versioning.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can be applied to current versions and previous versions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Following actions can now be done.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Transition to infrequenct access after a minimum of 30 days since creation date ( files need to be minimum 128kb )&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Archived to glacier storage class ( 30 days after IA, if relevant ).&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Permenantly Delete Objects&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CloudFront
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Edge Locations - This is the location where content will be cached.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Origin - This is the origin of all the files that the CDN will distribute. This can be either an S3 bucket, an EC2 instance, an Elastic Load balancer or Route53.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Distribution - This is the name given to the CDN with a collections of Edge Locations.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Web Distribution - Typically used for websites&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;RTMP - Used for Media Streaming&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Edge locations are not just readonly, you can write to them as well. ( Upload files to S3 ).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Object are cached for the life of the TTL ( time to live ) ( default ttl 24hours )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can clear cached objects, but you will be charged.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Securing your buckets.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;By default, all newly created buckets are &lt;strong&gt;PRIVATE&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can setup access control to your buckets using;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Bucket policies.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Access Control Lists.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;S3 buckets can be configured to create access logs which logs all the access requests made to the bucke. These logs can be stored in another bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encryption
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In-transit Encryption
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;SSL/TLS (HTTPS)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In rest
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Server Side Encryption
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;S3 Managed Keys SSE-S3&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;AWS Managed Keys SSE-KMS
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Allows you to monitor who decrypted which file when. (Audit trail)&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Customer provided Keys SSE-C&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Client Side Encryption
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Client uploads encrypted files.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storage Gateway
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;File Gateway - for flatfiles,  stored directly on S3.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volume Gateway (ISCI) - block based storage
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Stored Volumes - your on premises data is asynchronously backed up to S3.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Cached Volumes - frequently accessed data is cached on premises from S3.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gateway VIrtual Taped Library (VTL)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Used for backing up your data, from application like Netbackup, Backup Exec, Veam etc.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snowball
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snowball - Pure storage 50TB to 80TB&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snowball Edge - Both Compute and Storage Capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snowmobile - 100PB worth of storage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Understand what snowball is&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Understand what Import/Export is&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snowball can import / Export to S3&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 Transfer Acceleration
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can speed up S3 transfer speeds using CloudFront Edge locations, so you can upload files to s3 faster. Extra costs will apply. Greatest Impact on people who are further away geographically.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 static websites.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can S3 to host static websites.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Serverless&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very Cheap, scales automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Static only, cannot host dynamic sites.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CORS
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cross origin resource sharing&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Needed to enable cors on the resources bucket and state the URL for the origin that will be calling the bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Remeber to use the S3 website url and not the bucket URL, website url has the word website on it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you do a PUT object on S3 you will get a HTTP 200 success code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can load files much faster by enabling multipart upload.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the S3 FAQ!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DynamoDB Introduction</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/14/DynamoDB-Introduction.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-14T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/14/DynamoDB-Introduction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;dynamodb-101&quot;&gt;DynamoDB 101&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon DynamoDB is a fast and flexible NoSQL database service for all applications that need consistent, single-digit millisecond latency at any scale. It is a fully managed database and supports both document and key-value data models. Its flexible data model and reliable performance make it a great fit for mobile, web, gaming, ad-tech, IoT, and many other applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-facts-about-dynamodb-&quot;&gt;Quick Facts about DynamoDB ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stored on SSD Storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread Across 3 geographically distinct data centres.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventual Consistent Reads (Defaults)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consistency across all copies of data is usually reached within a second. Repeating a read after a short time should return the updated data. (Best Read Performance)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strongly Consistent Reads
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A strongly consistent read returns a result that reflects all writes that recieved a successful response prior to the read.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-basics&quot;&gt;The Basics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Items ( Think a row of data in table )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attributes ( Think a column of data in a table )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;DynamoDB can have 35 levels of nesting currently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing&quot;&gt;Pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provisioned Throughput Capacity
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Write throughput $0.0065 per hour for every 10 units&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read throughput $0.0065 per hour for every 50 units&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First 25 GB stored per month is free.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storage costs of $0.25 per month there after.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets assume that your application needs to perform 1 million writes and 1 million reads per day, while storing 28GB of data. First, you need to calculate how many writes and reads per second you need. 1 million evenly spread writes per day is equivalent to 1,000,000 ( writes ) / 24 ( hours ) / 60 ( minutes ) / 60 ( seconds ) = 11.6 writes per second. A DynamoDB write capacity unit can handle 1 write per second, so you need 12 write capacity units. For write throughput you are charged $0.0065 for every 10 units.
So ($0.0065/10) * 12 * 24 = $0.1872 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, to handle 1 million strongly consistent reads per day, you need 12 Read Capacity Units. For read throughput you are charged $0.0065 for every 50 units.
So ( $0.0065/50 ) * 12 * 24 = $0.0374 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storage costs is 0.25 per GB per month. Lets assume our database is 28GB. We get the first 25GB for free so we only pay for 3GB of storage which is $0.75 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total Cost = $0.1872 per day + $0.0374 per day Plus Storage of 0.75 per month
( 30 x ( $0.1872 + $0.0374 )) $0.75 = $7.488&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Free Tier You Get
25 Read Capacity Units
25 Write Capacity Units&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;easiest-way-to-learn-dynamodb&quot;&gt;Easiest Way to Learn DynamoDB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play with DynamoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Database Essentials</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/14/Database-Essentials.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-14T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/database/2018/06/14/Database-Essentials</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-relational-database-&quot;&gt;What is a relational database ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relational databases are what most of us are all used to. They have been around since 70’s. Very similar to the traditional spread sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Row&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fields ( Columns )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relational Database Types&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL Server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oracle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MySQL Server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PostgresSQL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aurora&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MariaDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Read the FAQ for RDS and DynamoDB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non Relational Databases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Database
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Collection        = Table&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Document          = Row&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Key Value Pairs   = Field&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-database-warehousing-&quot;&gt;What is Database Warehousing ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used for business intelligence. Tools like Cognos, Jaspersoft, SQL Server Reporting Services, Oracle Hyperion, SAP NetWeaver. Used to pull in very large and complex data sets. Usually used by management to do queries on data (such as current performance vs target etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oltp-vs-olap&quot;&gt;OLTP VS OLAP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online transaction processing verses online analytics processing are 2 different things interms of the types of queries you run on a database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OLTP example : Pulls up a row of data such as Name, Date, Address to Deliver to, Delivery Status etc.
OLAP example : Figure out the net profit for a digital radio product.
    * Sum of radios sold in EMEA
    * Sum of radios sold in Pacific
    * Unit cost of radio in rach region
    * Sales price of each radio
    * Sales price - unit cost&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Warehousing databases use different type of architechture both from a database perspective and insfrastructure layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;elasticache&quot;&gt;Elasticache&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ElasticCache is a web service that makes it easy to deploy, operate, and such an in-memory cache in the cloud.The service improves the performance of web applications by allowing you to retrieve information from fast, amanged, in-memory caches, instead of relying entirely on slower disk-based databases. ElasticCache supports two open-source in-memory caching engines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Memcached&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;database-migration-service&quot;&gt;Database Migration Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annouced at re:invent 2015. Allows you to migrate your production database to AWS. Once the migration has started, AWS manages all the complexities of the migration process like data type transformation, compression, and parallel transfer ( for faster data transfer ) while ensuring that data changes to the source data that occur during the migration process are automatically relicated to the target.
AWS schema conversion tool automatically converts the source database schema and a majority of the custom code, including views, stored procedures, and functions, to a format compatible with the target database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aws-database-types---summary&quot;&gt;AWS Database Types - Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RDS - OLTP
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SQL&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;MySQL&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;PostgresSQL&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Oracle&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aurora&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;MariaDB&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DynamoDB - No SQL&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RedShift - OLAP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elasticache - In Memory Caching
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Memcached&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Redis&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DMS - Database Migration Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Storage Gateway</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/Storage-Gateway.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/Storage-Gateway</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;AWS Storage Gateway, is a service that connects an on-premises software appliance with cloud-based storage to provide seamless and secure integration between an organization’s on premises IT environment and AWS’s storage infrastructure. The service enables you to securely store data to the AWS cloud for scalable and cost-effective storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS Storage Gateway Software Appliance is available for download as a virtual machine (VM) image that you install on a host in your data center. Storage Gateway support either VMware ESXi or Microsoft Hyper-V. Once youve installed your gateway and associated it with your AWS account though the activation process, you use the AWS Management Console to create the storage gateway option that is right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-types-of-storage-gateways&quot;&gt;4 types of storage gateways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File Gateway (NFS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows you store flat files in S3 ( word documents, pictures, pdf’s, etc )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volume Gateways ( iSCSI ) This for block based storage, maybe a volume attached to a VM.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stored Volume ( Gateway Stored Volumes )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cached Volume ( Gateway Cached Volumes )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tape Gateway ( VTL ) Backup and archiving solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;file-gateway&quot;&gt;File Gateway&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files are stored as objects in your S3 buckets, accessed through a Network File System (NFS) mount point. Ownership, permissions, and timestamps are durably stored in S3 in the user-metadata of the object associated with the file. Once objects are transferred to S3, they can be managed as native S3 objects, and bucket policies such as versioning, lifecycle management, and cross-region replication apply directly to objects stored in your bucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volume-gateway&quot;&gt;Volume Gateway&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volume interface presents your applications with disks volumes using iSCSI block protocol. Data written to these volumes can be asynchronously backed up as point-in-time snapshots of your volumes, and stored in the cloud as Amazon EBS snapshots. Snapshots are incremental backups that capture only changed blocks. All snapshots storage is also compressed to minimize your storage charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;stored-volumes&quot;&gt;Stored Volumes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stored volumes let you store your primary data locally, while asynchronously backing up that data to AWS. Stored volumes provide your on-premises applications with low-latency access to their entire datasets, while providing durable, off-site backups. You can create storage volumes and mount them as iSCSI devices from your on-premises application servers. Data written to your stored volumes is asynchronously backed upto Amazon Simple Storage Service ( Amazon S3 ) in the form of Amazon Elastic Block Store ( Amazon EBS ) snapshots. 1GB - 16TB in size for Stored Volumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cached-volumes&quot;&gt;Cached Volumes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cached volumes lets you use Amazon Simple Storage Service ( Amazon S3 ) as your primary data storage while retaining frequently accessed data locally in your storage gateway. Cached volumes minimize the need to scale your on-premises storage infrastructure, while still providing your applications with low-latency access to their frequently accessed data. You can create storage volumes upto 32 TB in size and attach to them as iSCSI devices from your on-premises application servers. Your gateway stores data that you write to these volumes in Amazon S3 and retains recently read data in your on-premises storage gateway’s cache and upload buffer storage. 1GB - 32 TB in size for Cached Volumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;taped-gateway&quot;&gt;Taped Gateway&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tape Gateway offers a durable, cost-effective solution to archive your data in the AWS Cloud. The VTL interface it provides lets you leverage your existing tape-based backup application infrastructure to store data on virtual tape cartridges that you create on your tape gateway. Each tape gateway is preconfigured with a media changer and tape drives, which are available to your existing client backup applications as iSCSI devies. You add tape cartridges as you to archive your data. Supported by NetBackup, Backup Exec, Veam etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File Gateway - For flat files, stored directly on S3 - Not os’s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volumes Gateways (block based storage)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stored Volumes - Entire Dataset is stored on site is asynchronously backed up to S3.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cached Volumes - Entire Dataset is stored on S3 and most frequently accessed data is kept on site.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gateway Virtual Tape Library ( VTL )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Used for backup and uses popular backup applications like NetBackup, Backup Exec, Veam etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Security and Encryption</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/S3-Security-and-Encryption.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/S3-Security-and-Encryption</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default, all newly created buckets are &lt;strong&gt;PRIVATE&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can setup access control to your buckets using;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bucket Policies - Permissions are applied to the entier bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access Control List - You can apply different permissions to different objects in the buckets.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 Buckets can be configured to create access logs which log all the requests made to the S3 bucket. This can be done to another bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encryption&quot;&gt;Encryption&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In transit ( When sending object to and from your PC )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SSL/TLS Encryption ( HTTPS )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At Rest ( When the objects are either in your PC or in the Server )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Server Side Encryption
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;S3 Managed Keys - SSE-S3&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;AWS Key Management Service ( AWS KMS ) - Managed Keys - SSE-KMS
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;These keys provide an audit trail, lets you know who has been using the keys.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Who has been decrypting what and when was it done.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Server Side Encryption with Customer Provided Keys - SSE-C&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Client Side Encryption ( You encrypt the files and then you upload them to S3 )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Lifecycle Management</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/S3-Lifecycle-Management.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/S3-Lifecycle-Management</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be used in conjunction with versioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be applied to current versions and previous versions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Following actions can now be done:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Transition to the standard infrequently accessed storage class
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;File sizes have to be bigger than 128kb and a minimum 30 days after creation.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Archive it to glacier storage class ( 30 days after IA, if relevant )&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Permanently Delete&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Cross Region Replication</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/S3-Cross-Region-Replication.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/S3-Cross-Region-Replication</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create 2 buckets one in london, and sydney&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enable Cross Region Replication on the london bucket
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In order for Cross Region Replication to work, you need both buckets with versioning enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can enable CRR on just a prefix on a bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set the bucket storage class from standard to IA.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hit save!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Existing objects will not be replicated into both the buckets, Only new objects get replicated into the other buckets&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to copy your current items in bucket one to bucket two.
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 cp &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--recursive&lt;/span&gt; s3://[bucket_1] s3://[bucket_2]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Items that have been copied over, by default has permission set to private.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you delete an item from bucket 1, it sets a delete marker on bucket 1 and does the same on bucket 2.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you delete the delete marker on bucket 1 it does not delete on bucket 2.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you revert to an older version in bucket 1, you must do so in bucket 2, because the changes are not refelcted automatically in bucket 2.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Versioning Must be enabled on both the source and destination buckets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Region must be unique.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Files in an existing must be replicated across regions manually, otherwise it does not get replicated automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot replicate to multiple bucket or daisy chain it at this time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;delete markers are replicated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;deleting individual version or delete markers will not be replicated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding what cross region replication is at a high level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CloudFront</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/CloudFront.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/13/CloudFront</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A content delivery network (CDN) is a system of distributed servers (network) that delivers webpages and other web content to a user based on the geographic locations of the user, the origin of the webpage and a content delivery server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon cloudfront can be used to deliver your entire website, including dynamic, static, streaming, and interactive content using a global network of edge locations. Requests for your content are automatically routed to the nearest edge location, so content is delivered with the best possible performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon CloudFront is optimized to work with other Amazon web services, like amazon simple storage service, amazon elastic cloud compute, amazon elastic load balancing, and amazon route 53. Amazon CloudFront also works seamlessly  with any Non-Aws origin server, which stores the original, definitive versions of your files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-terminology&quot;&gt;Key terminology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edge Location&lt;/strong&gt; - This is the location where content will be cached. This is seperate to an AWS Region/AZ.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Edge Locations are not &lt;strong&gt;READ-ONLY&lt;/strong&gt;. You can &lt;strong&gt;WRITE&lt;/strong&gt; to them too. ( ie put an object on to them ). This will be replicated back to the origin server.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Objects are cached for the life of the TTL ( Time To Live )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can clear cached objects, but you will be charged.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origin&lt;/strong&gt; - This is the origin of all the files that the CDN will distribute. This can be either an S3 bucket, an EC2 Instance, an Elastic Load Balancer or Route53.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distribution&lt;/strong&gt; - This is the name given to the CDN which consists of a collection of Edge Locations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web Distribution&lt;/strong&gt; - Typically used for Websites.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RTMP&lt;/strong&gt; - Used for Media Streaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lab&quot;&gt;LAB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a bucket in s3 to be used with CloudFront.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload an image to that bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goto CloudFront and click on create distribution network.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on get start under Web.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the s3 bucket on the origin domain name. (dropdown menu)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select Yes for restricting bucket access.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a new identity for bucket access.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update bucket policy to grant read permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under default cache behaviour Viewer protocol policy Redirect HTTP to HTTPS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restrict Viewer Access ( Use signed urls or signed cookies ) if you want to have restrictions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit save and it should be deployed in around 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also enable geo restrictions
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;either black countries or whitelist countries but not both.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to remove an object from the cache immedietely ( Costs MONEY ), you can do so by creating an Invalidation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After youre done with setting up, make sure you delete the distribution network because this does cost you money.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;First select the distribution network, and click on disable (15 - 30) mins later you will be able to click on delete.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Enable Versioning</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/12/S3-Enable-Versioning.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-12T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/12/S3-Enable-Versioning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loggin to the aws console and head over to aws s3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a new bucket, click next instead of create.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enable versioning and click next until bucket is created.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once versioning has been enabled for a bucket.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You cannot remove versioning from the bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can stop the bucket from creating more versions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you want to completely remove versioning from the bucket, create a new bucket, transfer everything to that bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you deleted an object, you can restore that object as well. You will be able to restore it to any point in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stores all versions of an object (including all writes and even if you object)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great Backup tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once enabled, Versioning cannot be disabled, only suspended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrated with Life cycle rules.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Versioning’s MFA Delete capability, which uses multi-factor authentication, can be used to provide an additional layer of security. ( bucket level and object level )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Serverless Website</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/Serverless-Website.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-11T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/Serverless-Website</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This will be example of the simplest serverless website possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First we will need to create a lambda function
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select python 3.6 for the language&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;add the following code to your lambda&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;lambda_handler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;event&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;In lambda_handler&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;statusCode&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;headers&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;*&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;body&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;This response is from a lambda function running in ohio!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;resp&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now set the trigger for your lambda function as API Gateway.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Give it any name you want.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Save your lambda settings&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Go to API Gateway and make sure its a get request.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Go to stages and get the GET method URL.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;See if the URL gives back the response you expect.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a bucket in S3 with static website hosting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;add the following index.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;request&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xhttp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;XMLHttpRequest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xhttp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;onreadystatechange&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;readyState&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;200&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getElementById&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;demo&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;innerHTML&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;responseText&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xhttp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;GET&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;API GATEWAY URL&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xhttp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;send&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;align=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;center&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Hello people&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;onclick=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;request()&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Click me!&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;demo&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have added the API Gateway url in the code above, It should work accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is how you build a serverless website with S3, Lambda and API Gateway!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Wesbite</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/S3-Wesbite.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-11T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/S3-Wesbite</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hosting static content with S3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a bucket with a name you would like.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goto bucket properties and select static website hosting.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You would want to select the option &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Use this bucket to host a website&lt;/code&gt;. Select the name for the index document and the error document.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can add in the redirection rules if you have any.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hit save.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you upload your files make sure you enable public read access on your file.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You website will return Access denied XML file otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You website will be available at http://[bucketname].s3-website-[region].amazonaws.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easiest way to break this website is to disable the public read access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cors&quot;&gt;CORS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in order for your static website in one bucket to access another javascript/css/images on another bucket. You need to go to the bucket with resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on bucket permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select CORS configuration from the dropdown list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in the line which says &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;AllowedOrigin&amp;gt;*&amp;lt;/AllowedOrigin&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; replace the * with the URL of the website that will be accessing these resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That will prevent all the errors caused by CORS not being configured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 Lab</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/S3-Lab.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-11T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/S3-Lab</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;S3 Buckets are managed at a global level, even two different aws accounts wont be able to have the same bucket name. Since bucketnames are used in a DNS namespace. Every bucket has a web address. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://s3-[region].amazonaws.com/[bucketname]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can have logging enabled in your bucket, this logs on all the activities that goes on in your bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can set tags to keep track of costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default all buckets are private, you can grant public access to a given bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default S3 Log delivery group does not have permission to write to buckets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you do an upload containing 2 objects, it will say one upload successful on successful upload. Since both the objects were uploaded in one upload.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you click on the link for an object, (which is given in the object propertise) by default it will give you an XML error page with access denied. You will have to make the object public readable in order to get rid of this. ( Object -&amp;gt; More -&amp;gt; Make Public )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you would like to change who has permissions on the object, object -&amp;gt; permissions, and then you can add other aws accounts or make it public.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you goto the object propertise, and click on storage class. Here you will be able to change the storage class from Standard to Infrequent Access or Reduced Redundency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the object propertise you even have encryption, (This is server side encryption).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also add in your own metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also add in tags for the object. ( Objects within the bucket dont inherit the buckets tags )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimum size of objects in S3 object is 0 bytes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;on the bucket propertise you can enable ( By default everything is turned off )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Versioning of all the objects in the bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access logs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Static Website hosting&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tags&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Transfer Acceleration&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Events - Recieve notifications when there are changes made to your bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Requester Pays&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are two ways to control the access to your S3 buckets
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access Control Lists&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bucket Policies
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;You can use policy generator to help you generate the json.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the management on bucket overview page
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can add rules for bucket lifecycle management.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can create replications to add buckets to other regions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can view bucket analytics&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can view bucket metrics&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can also view bucket inventory&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buckets are universal namespaced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload an object to S3 receive HTTP 200 code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3, S3 IA, S3 RR&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encryption
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Client Side Encryption&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Server Side Encryption
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Server Side Encryption with amazon S3 Managed Keys (SSE-S3)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Server Side Encryption with KMS (SSE-KMS)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Server Side Encryption with Customer Provided Keys (SSE-C)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Control Access to Buckets using either a bucket ACL or using Bucket Policies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default buckets are private and all objects stored inside them are private.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 101</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/S3-101.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-11T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/storage/2018/06/11/S3-101</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-s3&quot;&gt;What is S3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S3 provides developer and IT teams with secure durable, highly scalable object storage. Amazon S3 is easy to use, with a simple web service interface to store and retrieve any amount of data from anywhere on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 is a safe place to store your files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is Object based storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The data is spread across multiple devices and facilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s3-basics&quot;&gt;S3 basics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Object based storage i.e allows you to upload files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Files can be from 0 Byte to 5 TB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is unlimited storage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Files are stored in buckets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 is a universal namespace, that is names must be unique globally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 urls are as follows
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;https://s3-[region].amazonaws.com/[bucketname]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;https://s3-eu-west.amazonaws.com/acloudguru&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;https://s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/godsoflinux.com&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you upload a file to S3, you will receive a HTTP 200 code if the upload successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-consistency-model-for-s3&quot;&gt;Data Consistency Model for S3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read after write consistency for PUTS of new objects.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When you put a new object in S3, you will get immediate consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventual Consistency for overwrite PUTS and DELETES ( can take sometime to propergate ).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You dont get immediate updates when you update or delete files from S3, It takes sometime for the objects to update.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updates to S3 is ATOMIC
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You are either going to get the old data or you are going to get the old data. You will not get partial parts of the old data and new data.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s3-is-a-simple-key-value-store&quot;&gt;S3 is a simple key value store&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;* S3 is object based, Objects consist of the following.
    * Key (This is the name of the object)
    * Value (This is simply the data and is made up of a sequence of bytes )
    * Version ID ( Important for versioning )
    * Metadata ( Data about the data you are storing )
    * Subresources
        * Access Control Lists ( Who can access this object )
        * Torrent ( Bittorrent protocol )
* S3 is lexicogrpahical, Ordered alphabetically on the key name. Its a design consideration for the application.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guarantee&quot;&gt;Guarantee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built for 99.99% Availability for the S3 platform,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Guarantee 99.9% availability. ( SLA service level agreement )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Guarantees 99.999999999% durability for S3 information. 9/11&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tiered Storage Available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lifecycle Management
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If your data is 30 days old, keep them in this particular storage tier.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Versioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encryption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure your data using Access Control Lists and Bucket Policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s3---storage-tiers--classes&quot;&gt;S3 - Storage Tiers / Classes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 - 99.99 availability, 99.999999999% durability, stored redundantly across multiple devices in multiple facilities and is designed to sustain the loss of 2 facilities concurrently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 - IA ( Infrequently Accessed ) For data that accessed less frequently, but requires rapid access when needed. Lower fee than S3, but you are charged a retreval fee.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduced Redundancy Storage - Designed to provide 99.99% durability and 99.99% availability of objects over a given year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glacier - Very cheap, but used for data archival only. It takes 3 - 5 hours to restore from Glacier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;charge&quot;&gt;Charge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Storage
* Requests
* Storage Management Pricing
* Data Transfer pricing
* Transfer acceleration
    * Amazon S3 Transfer Acceleration Enables Fast, easy and secure transfer of files over long distances between your end users and an S3 bucket. Transfer Acceleration takes advantage of Amazon CloudFront's globally distributed edge locations. As the data arrives at an edge location, data is routed to Amazon S3 over an optimized network path.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember that S3 is Object based i.e. allows you to upload files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File can be from 0 bytes to 5 TB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is unlimited storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Files are stored in buckets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 has a universal, that is, names for buckets must be unique globally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://s3-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/godsoflinux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read after write consistency for PUTS of new objects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventual Consistency on overwrites and deletes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3 Storage Classes / Tiers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;S3 ( durable, immedietely available, frequently accessed )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;S3 IA ( Infrequently Accessed, durable, immedietely available )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;S3 Reduced Redundency Storage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Glacier ( for archival data which can take 3 to 5 hours to access )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember the core fundementals of an S3 object
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Key (name)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Value (data)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version ID&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Metadata&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Subresources
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;ACL&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Torrent&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Object based storage only! (for files)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not install operating systems on it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Successful uploads will generate HTTP 200 status code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read the S3 FAQ before the exam!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Summary of EC2 Section</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/10/Summary-of-EC2-Section.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-10T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/10/Summary-of-EC2-Section</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fundemental Topic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember to read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/faqs/&quot;&gt;EC2 FAQ&lt;/a&gt; before going for the exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know the difference between the pricing models of EC2.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;On Demand&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spot&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reserved&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dedicated Hosts&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember for Spot Instances
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you terminate the instance, you pay for the hour.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If aws terminates the spot instance, you get the hour it was terminated in for free.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EC2 Instance Types.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Remember DRMCGIFTPX&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;D - Dense Storage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;R - Memory Optimized&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;M - General Purpose ( Production )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;C - Compute Optimized&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;G - Graphics Intensive&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I - Storage Optimized&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;F - Field Programmable Gate arrays&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;T - Low Cost General Purpose&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;P - Graphics / General Purpose&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;X - Memory Optimized ( eXtreme Memory Optimized )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EBS Consists of
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SSD - General Purpose - GP2 - ( Up to 10,000 IOPS ).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SSD - Provisioned IOPS - IO1 - ( More than 10,000 IOPS ).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HDD - Throughput optimized - ST1 - Frequently accessed workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HDD - Cold - SC1 - less frequently accessed data.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;HDD - Magnetic - Standard - Cheap, infrequently accessed storage.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot mount 1 EBS Volume to multiple EC2 instances, instead use EFS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Termination Protection is turned off by default, You must turn on termination protection if you would like that safety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On an EBS backed storage, the default action on instance termination is deleting the EBS volume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Root Volumes cannot be encrypted by default unless you use a thirdparty tool to encrypt the root volume. (eg: Bitlocker )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Additional Volumes can be encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volumes VS Snapshots
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volumes exists on EBS
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Virtual Harddisks&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots exists on S3&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can take snapshots of a volume, this will store that volume on S3.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots are point in time copies of that volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots are incremental, this means that only the blocks that have changed since your last snapshots are moved to S3. ( first snapshots takes a while, but afterwards its fine )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volumes VS Snapshots - Security
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots of encrypted volumes are encrypted automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volumes that are restored from snapshots are encrypted automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can share snapshots with other AWS accounts, or publicly on the AWS market place, only if they are not encrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snapshots of Root Device Volumes.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To create a snapshot for Amazon EBS volume that serve as root device, you should stop the instance before taking the snapshot ( but can be done on a running instance ).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EBS vs Instance Store Volumes
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Instance Store volumes are sometimes called Ephemeral Storage.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Instance Store volumes cannot be stopped, If the underlying host fails, you will loose your data.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;EBS backed instances can be stopped, You will not loose the data on this instance if it is stopped.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can reboot both, and you will not loose your data.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;By default, both ROOT volumes will be deleted on termination, however with EBS volumes, you can tell AWS to keep the root device volume. ( set a FLAG )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to take a snapshot from the RAID Array?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Problem - Take a snapshot, the snapshot excludes data held in the cache by applications and the OS. This tends not to matter on a single volume, however using multiple volumes in a RAID array, this can be a problem due to interdependencies of the array.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Solution - Take an application consistent snapshot.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Stop the application from writing to disk&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Flush all caches to the disk.
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Freeze the file system.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Unmount the RAID Array.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Shutdown the associated EC2 instance.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Machine Images
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;AMI’s are regional - You can only launch an AMI from the region in which it is stored. However you can copy AMI’s to other regions using the console, commandline or the Amazon EC2 API.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloudwatch Monitoring
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Standard monitoring is enabled by default for EC2. ( Every 5 minutes )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can enable Detailed Monitoring ( Every minute ).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CloudWatch is for performance monitoring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CloudTrail is for Auditing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What can you create with CloudWatch ?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dashboards - Create awesome dashboards to see what is happening with your aws environment.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Alarms - Allows you to set alarms that notify you when particular thresholds are hit.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Events - CloudWatch Events help you to respond to state changes in your aws resources.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Logs - CloudWatch logs help you to aggregate, monitor, and store logs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Roles are more secure than storing your access key and secret access key on individual EC2 instances.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Roles are much easier to manage than having secret access keys around in terms of security.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If you loose your security key, you will have to delete the old ones and create a new one.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Roles can now be assigned to an EC2 instance after it has been provisioned using both the commandline and the AWS console.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Roles are global&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instance Metadata
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Used to get information about an instance ( such as public IPV4 )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;curl http://169.254.169.254/latest/meta-data/&lt;/code&gt; will all the available information.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EFS
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Support the Network File System Version 4 protocol (NFSv4)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You only pay for the storage you use ( no pre-provisioning required )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can scale upto petabytes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can support thousands of concurrent NFS connections&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data is stored across multiple AZ’s within a region.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read After Write Consistency&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambda
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;AWS lambda is a compute service where you can upload your code and create lambda function. AWS Lambda takes care of provisioning and managing the servers that you use to run the code. You dont have to worry about the operating systems, patching, scaling, etc. You can use Lambda in the following ways.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As an event driven compute service, AWS runs your code in response to events. These events could be changes to your data in an Amazon S3 bucket or an Amazon DynamoDB table.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As a compute service to run your code in response to HTTP requests using Amazon API gateway or API calls made using AWS SDK’s. This is what we use at A Cloud Guru.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SDK Exam Tips</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/10/SDK-Exam-Tips.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-10T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/10/SDK-Exam-Tips</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;know-the-available-sdks&quot;&gt;Know the available sdks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/tools/&quot;&gt;official documentation on sdk’s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android, IOS, Nodejs (WEB)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Java&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;.Net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nodejs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C++&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sdk-default-region&quot;&gt;SDK Default Region&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Default Region - US-EAST-1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some have default regions (Java)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some do not (Node.js)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If a region is not specified it will default back to US-EAST-1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lambda</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/10/Lambda.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-10T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/10/Lambda</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-lambda-&quot;&gt;What is lambda ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS Lambda is a compute service where you can upload your code and create a Lambda function. AWS Lambda takes care of provisioning and managing the servers that you use to run the code. You dont have to worry about operating systems, patching, scaling, etc. You can use Lambda in the following ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As an &lt;strong&gt;Event Driven Compute Service&lt;/strong&gt; where AWS Lambda runs your code in response to events. These events could be changes to data in an Amazon S3 bucket or an Amazon DynamoDB table.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a compute service to run your code in response to HTTP requests using Amazon API Gateway or API calls made using AWS SDKs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-a-lambda&quot;&gt;Create a lambda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Services-&amp;gt;Compute-&amp;gt;Lambda-&amp;gt;Create Function&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select Blue Print
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Author from scratch&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure Triggers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Available Triggers
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;API Gateway&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;AWS IoT&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Alexa Skills Kit&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Alexa Smart Home&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;CloudFront&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;CloudWatch Events&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;CloudWatch Logs&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;CodeCommit&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Cognito Sync Trigger&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;DynamoDB&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Kinesis&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;S3&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;SNS&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select API Gateway&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure Function
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Available Languages
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;C#&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Nodejs&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lambda-pricing&quot;&gt;Lambda Pricing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of requests
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;First 1 million requests are free. $0.20 per 1 million requests afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duration
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Duration is calculated from the time your code begins executing until it returns or otherwise terminates, rounded up to the nearest 100ms. The pricing depends on the amount of memory you allocate to your function. You are charged $0.00001667 for every GB/second used.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros-on-lambda&quot;&gt;Pros on Lambda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No Servers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuous Scaling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Super Super Super cheap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-tips&quot;&gt;Exam Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambda scales out ( not up ) automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambda functions are independent, 1 event = 1 function.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambda is serverless.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambdas can trigger other lambda functions, 1 event can = x functions if functions trigger other functions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Architectures can get extremely complicated, AWS x-ray allows you to debug what is happening.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambda can do things globally, It can be used to backup S3 buckets to other S3 buckets etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know which services can trigger lambda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambdas can run for at most 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;other-serverless-services&quot;&gt;Other serverless services&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;API Gateway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DynamoDB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Definetely not EC2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2 Instance Metadata</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/09/EC2-Instance-Metadata.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/09/EC2-Instance-Metadata</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-requisite&quot;&gt;Pre-requisite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an ec2 instance ready when you wanna start this lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to see a list of all the metadata for the ec2 instance you’re on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl http://169.254.169.254/latest/meta-data
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That should list out all the options available for you. For you to obtain the IPV4 public address for the ec2 instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl http://169.254.169.254/latest/public-ipv4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That should give you the public ipv4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the same concept with any programming language to get the ec2 instance metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2 Elastic Load Balancer</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/09/EC2-ELB.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/09/EC2-ELB</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;types-of-load-balancers&quot;&gt;Types of load balancers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application load balancers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Work at layer 7 ( Preferred Method )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Newest 2016&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classic load balancer
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Layer 4 routing TCP layer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-load-balancer&quot;&gt;Creating a Load balancer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Services-&amp;gt;EC2-&amp;gt;[left panel]ELB-&amp;gt;Create Load Balancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select Classic Load Balancer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define Load Balancers
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure its not an internal load balancer.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If youre using default vpc keep advanced vpc disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;leave the rest as default&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assign Security Group.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Leave it as default.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure Health Check.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use HTTP&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set ping path as health.html&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set response timeout as 2 seconds&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Interval at 5 seconds&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unhealthy threshold 2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Healthy threshold 3&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add your EC2 Instances&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add tags!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very important to keep track for the cost tracking&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review and launch -&amp;gt; Create&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will take sometime to register the load balancer and the load balancer to come online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instance monitored by ELB are reported as ; InService, or OutofService&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health Checks check the instace health by doing a http request and getting the expected response from it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hace their own DNS name. Never will be given an IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the ELB FAQ for Classic Load Balancers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>AWS Study Guide</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/exam/study/guide/2018/06/09/AWS-Study-Guide.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-09T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/exam/study/guide/2018/06/09/AWS-Study-Guide</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distributed-practice&quot;&gt;Distributed Practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend a little bit of time every day of the month. Spreading out the learning makes things stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;varied--interleaved-practise&quot;&gt;Varied / Interleaved Practise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequently change tasks and topics so that you are forced to think about the material in different ways. Easier to learn new things by incoperating and reinforcing previously-learned material. Let your existing &lt;strong&gt;mental model&lt;/strong&gt; help you learn new things. Use your mental model often since it will help you strengthen and refine it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spaced-repetition&quot;&gt;Spaced Repetition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review Information before you forget it completely. Revisit information when your mental model has improved. Spread out the learning time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;zooming-in--zooming-out&quot;&gt;Zooming in &amp;amp; Zooming out&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wikipedia : [A]bstraction is a technique for arranging complexity of computer systems. It works by establishing a level of complexity on which a person interacts with the system, suppressing the more complex details below the current level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstractions&lt;/strong&gt; are very important in software systems. It is the foundation of amazon web services. (&lt;em&gt;but just really anything in technology is&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your goal is to architect and build systems. Think about the data flow through your entire system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nothing exists in isolation, services interconnect, the systems interacts with other systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change over time is a key dimension in all tradeoff decisions, a “perfect” system that cannot be changed is fundementally broken, because the context around that system will eventually change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technically debt, what you do now determines how easy it will be to make changes later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mental-models&quot;&gt;Mental Models&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You remember things you understand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The image of the world around us, which we carry in our head, is just a model. Nobody in his head imagines all the world, government or country. He has only selected concepts, and relationships between them, and uses those to represent the real system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-mental-model&quot;&gt;What is a mental model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A simplified representation of reality that your mind uses to anticipate events or draw conclusions. A way to describe what your brain builds when you understand something. The way your brain organizes information it learns into heirarchies, its when you use logic instead of memorization. Recognizing patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;value-proposition&quot;&gt;Value Proposition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predictive capability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quicker and easier learning: Understanding vs Memorization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brain is better at remembering related concepts than unrelated details.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More memorization can dilute older information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More understanding improves mental models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-build-a-mental-model&quot;&gt;How to build a mental model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double loop learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;single-loop-learning&quot;&gt;Single loop learning&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is error correction by following the rules and operating norms when solving problem. Some thing like a feedback control loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;double-loop-learning&quot;&gt;Double loop learning&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is error correction by changing and critically questioning the rules and operating norms when solving problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This involves more thinking outside the box.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creativity is a must.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thinking outside the operating norms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows us to question which situation is the best to reach our end goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;progression--building-the-mental-model-&quot;&gt;Progression ( Building the mental model )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When new information clashes with your mental model, you will have to rebuild your mental model. &lt;strong&gt;Forced rebuilds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eventually becomes more robust and require fewer major changes, which results for efficient assimilation of info, high-efficiency learning and functional expertise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elaborative investigation uses questions like “why?” and “how?” to understand the meaning of information to be learned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socratic Method, based on asking and answering questions to stimulate critical thinking and to draw out ideas and underlying presumptions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Five whys - used to learn the root cause of a defect or problem by repeating the question “why?”. Each answer forms the basis of the next question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep asking this about everything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why does this service or feature exist? why would someone want it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why does it work the way it does?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why are the limits set the way they are?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they for my protection?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they to help AWS manage scaling?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they trying to encourage/force me to use better designs?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they implementation artifacts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&quot;&gt;What?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What assumptions have i made?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What assumptions have aws made?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the key purpose of this service/feature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when&quot;&gt;When?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When does the abstractions leak? When does what i know ( believe ) change?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Does it break under load?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;During certain kinds of outages? ( AZ down? Other service having problems? )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Randomly but rare? ( Amortized costs? Network glitches? )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When might i get throttled or hit service limits?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Which ones are fixed in stone?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Which ones can be changed?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-&quot;&gt;How ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is this similar to what i’ve seen before?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is this different from what i’ve seen before?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did they build this?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Based on my understanding, what should be the limitations?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Am i right about this?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can i test what i believe?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does AWS handle failures?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do i handle failures?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does this intergrate with other services?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-&quot;&gt;Who ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is the target for this service?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service offerings target real user scenarios - based on customer feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrate those into your mental model to make better predictions about how it should / does work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-teaching-others-can-help&quot;&gt;How teaching others can help&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;teaching&quot;&gt;Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forces you to communicate what you have learned. Requires you to understand the material more deeply. May also result in further questions that you hadnt considered. Explaining in detail to someone else will concrete these in your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dive-in&quot;&gt;Dive in!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a forum question that interests you. Research it until you can answer it. With full explanations. Make your response defensible, not just an opinion or guess. Use quotes from and links to official documentation!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;30-second-summary&quot;&gt;30 Second Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On any topic or technology.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recite a 15 to 30 second summary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Key strengths.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Key weaknesses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How it interacts with other services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;visualization&quot;&gt;Visualization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not just vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The words “visualization” and “imagery” are in some ways misleading. while the domiant sense is usually vision, visualization does not just involve seeing. The more senses you involve, the stronger the effect. Hear a switch click when you turn it on, or feel an engine turn over and the vibrations when you start it. Smell fuel when you check a fuel tank.. All these can significantly improve how your visualizations work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Imagine yourself as a network packet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On your way home ( a client system ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To work ( a load-balanced server in a VPC ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driving and turning along roads ( network hops, routing, load balancing ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And passing security checkpoints (firewalls, network ACLs, security groups).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some are machines that always check your papers ( stateless; nACLs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Others have guards that remember you on the way back ( stateful;SGs )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pdca&quot;&gt;PDCA&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-pdca&quot;&gt;What is PDCA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plan what youre going to do to learn some new material&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do what you planned; set about actually learning it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check how well that plan worked-both how easy and how effective it was.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adjust
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Adjust your plan for future learning, emphasizing techniques that worked well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-to-do-before-the-exam&quot;&gt;What to do before the exam&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;month-before&quot;&gt;Month before&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read AWS Certification FAQ
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Think about the exam process.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read Exam blueprint
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pay attention to the exam waiting in each content domain&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read every line item.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take ACLOUD.Guru certification course final practice exam
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Take for first time, as assessment.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Repeat until consistently scoring 100%.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Understand why every incorrect answer is wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unserstand why every correct answer is right.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read certification course forum posts about the exam feedback.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read throught the 20-30 highest-ranked from the last 2-8 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Read through all exam related posts from the last 2-8 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;week-or-two-before&quot;&gt;Week or Two Before&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take aws practise exam for the first time.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Late enough to evaluate yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Early enough to refresh on weak areas.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Early enough to reschedule / cancel without penalty, if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Take screenshots!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rip the questions and responses apart!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the latest exam feedback forum posts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-before&quot;&gt;Day Before&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewatch training course summary lessons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review your own notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download some key course videos to phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read top forum posts with details to remember.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider reading most recent forum posts for very latest feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read AWS sample questions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review questions from AWS practise exam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review memorization items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evening-before&quot;&gt;Evening Before&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Double check details.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Exam location&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Exam time.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All Documents ( Govt-issued picture ID ) ( Additional ID ).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set out printed exam details.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metally prepare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;just-before&quot;&gt;Just Before&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Come early!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Last minute review notes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;watch key downloaded training videos&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to the bath room.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Validate IDs and the exam registration with proctor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lock up everything you have.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Empty every pocket of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>S3 CLI AND REGIONS</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/07/S3-CLI-AND-REGIONS.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-07T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/07/S3-CLI-AND-REGIONS</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch an EC2 instance with the default settings, and no roles attached to it.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;t2.micro&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Amazon linux AMI&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;default configuration settings&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;add to a security group which has HTTP, HTTPS and SSH from 0.0.0.0&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create 3 S3 buckets.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One in London&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One in Northern Virginia&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One in Sydney&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add some random objects to those buckets.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should be unique&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create a role with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;amazon s3 full access&lt;/code&gt; and attach it to your EC2.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SSH into your ec2 instances, and you can copy those items from your buckets into your ec2 instance
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 cp s3://[bucketname] ./
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This works regardless of which region the bucket is in, before you would have to provide the –region flag with the region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bash Scripting Lab</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/07/Bash-Scripting-Lab.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-07T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/07/Bash-Scripting-Lab</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this lab we are going to pass a bash script to the ec2 instance before it is launched to automate some of the tasks we want the instance to execute before we ssh in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create an ec2 instance to launch.
Make sure you assign the role s3-admin-access to this instance.
On the tab &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;3. Configure Instance&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Advanced Details -&amp;gt; User Data &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;!&lt;/code&gt;. Make sure As text option is selected. And then add then pass the following bash script to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Log file to log all the events&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;LOGFILE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/home/ec2-user/ONBOOT.log


&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Install updates to the server&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;yum update &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-y&lt;/span&gt; 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LOGFILE&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Install apache&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;yum install httpd &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-y&lt;/span&gt; 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LOGFILE&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Start the apache service and set the service to run on boot&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;service httpd start 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LOGFILE&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;chkconfig httpd on 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LOGFILE&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Copy website from s3 to /var/www/html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;aws s3 cp &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--recursive&lt;/span&gt; s3://[bucketname] /var/www/html/ 2&amp;amp;1 &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LOGFILE&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Startup script done installing essentials&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LOGFILE&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the instance gets launched, It should have setup the webserver and your file will be available when you head to the instance ip address on the browser. Also after you login, you be able to see the execution logs on the home directory. If anything did go wrong it should be on the logs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2 AWS CLI</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/06/EC2-AWS-CLI.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-06T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/06/EC2-AWS-CLI</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In order to get aws cli running, you need to create a user in IAM with programatic access. Save the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;credentials.csv&lt;/code&gt; file. &lt;strong&gt;You only get to download this once&lt;/strong&gt;. Only give user the permission for the resource you want the user to access, and nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spinning up a EC2 instance, run the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should give you an error saying, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;unable to locate credentails. You can configure credentials by running &quot;aws configure&quot;.&lt;/code&gt; So run the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws configure
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now enter the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Access Key ID&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Secret Access Key&lt;/code&gt; you downloaded when you created the IAM user with the programatic access. After that try the following command again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it should show you a list of all the buckets you have created on s3. If you dont have any buckets it will be empty. You can create a bucket with the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 mb s3://&amp;lt;enter your bucket name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Remember that your bucketname has to be unique across all the buckets that has ever been created in aws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for you to get help on a specific aws service, you can type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws [service] help&lt;/code&gt;. So for example to get help about s3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;help&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get help on a command of the service you can type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws [service] [command] help&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 mb &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;help&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now since we configured our aws cli to be using the credentials on the ec2 instance. This is risky since if someone did hack in they will use your credentials to do nasty things to your s3 buckets or more. The credentials are stored in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/.aws/credentials&lt;/code&gt;. Dont ever store these credentials in github, in your projects. The best way to do programatic resource management with scripts is to use an ec2 with the right role attached to it. And then ssh-ing into the machine. And then you can run whatever script you wanted to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to list all the running ec2 instances, run the command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws ec2 describe-instances
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see bunch of information here. and then in order to terminate any running instance type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws ec2 terminate-instances&lt;/code&gt;. You can get the instance id from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws describe-instances&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws ec2 describe-instances &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--instance-ids&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;enter instance id here]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;make sure you delete the user that you created for this unless you have specific access for you to do something simple on your own machine. To do this the safe way create a role with the required access in IAM. In situations where you have multiple ec2 instances with the credentials file, and the credentials files got leaked. You will need to delete the file and replace the in everysingle ec2 instance. Which can be done programatically, its still ugly. So the best way is to use roles on those ec2 instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the case where you want to have an ec2 instance do a bunch of tasks with s3. You should create the s3 admin access role and attach it to your ec2 instance. Also remember &lt;strong&gt;roles are available globally, you cannot create a role for a specific region&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;So after you have created an instance with the right role attached&lt;/em&gt;. You could double check on all the possible actions that is doable from this ec2 instance by going on to polices from the left side panel. Click on policies -&amp;gt; permissions. Here you can view both the json and gui version of all the actions that have been issued for the ec2 instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can click on a running instance -&amp;gt; Actions -&amp;gt; Instance Settings -&amp;gt; Attach / Replace IAM role, If you want to attach another IAM role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have added the S3 access to the role you attached to the ec2 instance. You can try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws s3 &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and now it should just work with out asking you to configure things. Even if you check the directory &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;~/.aws&lt;/code&gt; it should be empty. So even if your ec2 instance got compromised, you dont have to delete your access credentials.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2 AWS CLI DEV</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/06/EC2-AWS-CLI-DEV.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-06T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/06/EC2-AWS-CLI-DEV</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-create-a-new-ec2-instance&quot;&gt;To create a new ec2 instance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inorder to create a new ec2 instance from the commandline, we first need to know which AMI we want to use. We could pass the option &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;describe-images&lt;/code&gt; to the aws cli and we can get the list. But that would return you a huge list. To list out the images from amazon you can use the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws ec2 describe-images &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--owners&lt;/span&gt; amazon &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--filters&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Name=platform,Values=Linux1&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Name=root-device-type,Values=ebs&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can go to the console, get the SubnetID of the ec2 instance you are logged in. 
you also have to make sure you have a keypair on aws. Try the following command launch your instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws ec2 run-instances &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--image-id&lt;/span&gt; ami-165a0876 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--count&lt;/span&gt; 1 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--instance-type&lt;/span&gt; t2.micro &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--key-name&lt;/span&gt; MyKeyPair &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--security-groups-ids&lt;/span&gt; sg-d03bafb7 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--subnet-id&lt;/span&gt; subnet123abc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should have provisioned your ec2 instance if you do not have any problems in your command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to terminate instances, all you need to do is grab the instance ids and then type the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws ec2 terminate-instances &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--instance-ids&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;instance id]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful when you issue that command, it will completely destroy your ec2 instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commands&quot;&gt;Commands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Command&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws ec2 describe-instances&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;will show all the information about your instances&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws ec2 describe-images&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;will show all the information about all the available images. Be aware this will spam your terminal with a never ending list of json&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws ec2 run-instances&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;will create a new instance and launch&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;aws ec2 start-instances&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;will start a stopped instance&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dont get confused about start-instances and run-instances&lt;/strong&gt; start instances will not create a new instance! only run instance would create a new instance. And start instance will only start a stopped instance.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2 Security Groups</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-Security-Groups.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-Security-Groups</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Security Group is a Virtual Firewall, which controls traffic in and out of your ec2 instance. Ec2 instances are launched with one or more security groups attached to it. Multiple security groups can be applied to one ec2 instance. This is also the first line of defence against any security threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any change to the security group or implementing rules across security groups, comes into effect immedietly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security groups are stateful, any rules added as inbound rules allows outbound rules.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are not able to deny any traffic, you can only allow traffic since all traffic is blocked by default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your ec2 instances will be able to communicate with each other if they have the default security group attached to them, regarless of the region they are based off of.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to attach more than one security group to an instance which is already running, go to actions-&amp;gt;Networking-&amp;gt;Change Security Groups-&amp;gt; and check all the security groups you want to attach for the instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All inbound traffic is blocked by default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All outbound traffic is allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes to security group takes effect immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can any number of EC2 instances within a security group.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can have multiple security groups attached to an instance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security groups are stateful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot block specific IP Addresses using security groups, instead use Network Access Control Lists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can specify allow rules, but not deny rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2-EFS</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EFS.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EFS</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;elastic-file-system&quot;&gt;Elastic File System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aws elastic file system, is a storage service for EC2 instances. EFS is easy to use and provides a simple interface that allows users to create and configure file systems quickly and easily. With aws EFS, storage capacity is elastic, growing and shrinking automatically as you add and remove files so your applications have storage always when they need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supports the Network File System Version 4 (NFSv4) protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You only pay for the storage you use ( no pre-provisioning required ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can scale upto petabytes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can support thousands of concurrent NFS connections.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data is stored across multiple Availability Zones within a region.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read after Write consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block based storage, not object based storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-efs-volume&quot;&gt;Creating a EFS Volume&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way how it connects to EC2 instances is through your VPC. If you do not have any custom VPC’s you can connect them to the default VPC’s for the availability zones in your region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the VPC you want to connect the EFS to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the availability zones you want to assign them to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the availability zones, select the subnets you want them on, add the ip address you want it to have, and also attach the security groups for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the tags.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After reviewing it, Create the File System.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fantastic solution to have shared resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2 EBS Volumes</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EBS-Volumes.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EBS-Volumes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;lab&quot;&gt;LAB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to aws services, and then goto EC2. One the left side panel, select Volumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The EBS volume and the EC2 instance has to be in the same availability zone, in order for the volume to be attached to the EC2 instance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All root volumes will have a snapshot id, which relates to the machine image its running.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There will be no down time when you modify your volumes, ( change the Hard disk type / change the disk size ). You may run into performance issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With standard volumes, you will not be able to modify the volumes. ( ST1 - pure magnetic )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to spin up an EC2 instance with the same volume in another availability zone:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Goto Actions and create a snapshot.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add the required information on the form and click create.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Goto snapshots.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Click on Actions and Select Create a Volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can select any volume type / volume size.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select any availability zone that you want.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And attach it to the EC2 instance you want.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create a snapshot of the EBS volume you would like to move to another EC2 instance, Create a volume from that snapshot.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can go to snapshots and copy the snapshot to any other region, if you want to switch region.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can create an image from that snapshot in order to boot from that volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots are normally used for backups, Where as Images are used to create new volumes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure when you create an image its an image of one volume, when you want to boot off from this image later on.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can also create AMI’s directly from the snapshots, and then move it to another region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Root Device is where the operating system is installed at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volumes-and-snapshots&quot;&gt;Volumes and Snapshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volumes exists on EBS
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Virtual Hard Disk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snapshots exist on S3.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When you go to S3, you will not be able to see any buckets with the snapshots in there.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots are copies of Volumes at a given time.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Taking the second snapshot would only save the state of the blocks that have been modified, and moved to S3.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Your first snapshot will take some time to create, after the first one it wont take that long anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To create a snapshot of a Volume which serve as a Root Volume, you should stop the running instance. But it is possible to take a snapshot of the running instance Root Volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can create AMI’s from both Volumes and Snapshots.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can change the EBS Volume sizes on the fly, including changing the size and storage type.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volumes will &lt;strong&gt;ALWAYS&lt;/strong&gt; be in the same availability zone as the EC2 Instance.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To move an EC2 volume from one Availability Zone/Region to another, take a snap or an image of it, then copy it to the new Availability Zone/Region.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots of encrypted volumes are encrypted automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volumes restored from encrypted snapshots are encrypted automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can share snapshots, but only if they are unecrypted.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;These snapshots can be shared with other aws accounts or it can be made completely public.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do this lab at least 3 times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2-Lab-Summary</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/04/EC2-Lab-Summary.html"/>
   <updated>2018-06-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/06/04/EC2-Lab-Summary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-an-ec2-instance&quot;&gt;Creating an EC2 Instance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select a region which you want your EC2 instance to be at.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Older regions will have most of the different types of EC2 instances available, newer ones will have less.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select an AMI right after clicking on “Launch Instance”.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You have many flavours of AMI’s available.
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Amazon Linux AMI&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Red Hat Enterprise Linux&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;SUSE Linux Enterprise Server&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Server 16.04 LTS&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Windows Server&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version numbers of the above will change new version get adapted.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Amazon linux AMI comes with all the required built in tools and SDK’s installed. (Free Tier Eligible)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose an Instance Type
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;t2.micro (Free Tier Eligible)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure Instance Details
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Main setup page for Ec2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Under VPC you can select one of the subnets, there is one subnet for every single availability zone. &lt;strong&gt;You can never have one subnet that goes across multiple availability zones.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Selecting an IAM Role (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enable termination protection [ to prevent people from accidentally terminating the instance ]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Additional charges are applied for detailed monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Advanced details, you can pass in bootstrap scripts to automate tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add Storage
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select the required storage for the root volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;by default the &lt;strong&gt;root volume will be deleted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volume = virtual harddisk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the tags
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Help you to control costs.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Always do more than just name tags, drill down upto the department and staff id.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure Security Groups
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Its a virtual firewall&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set the services you want to allow, [ ssh, http, https ]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can restrict services to only from your IP.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review everything and Launch
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create a keypair.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Either upload your own public key or create your keypair on the web interface and download.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hit launch instance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connect-to-the-running-instance&quot;&gt;Connect to the running Instance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use ssh to connect to your instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh ec2-user@[your_ec2_instance_public_ip-address] &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;your_keypair.pem]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once logged in, it maybe a good idea to update the AMI &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo yum update&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-web-server&quot;&gt;Creating a web server&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install apache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;yum install httpd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/var/www/html/&lt;/code&gt; and then add some &lt;em&gt;HTML&lt;/em&gt; in the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-HTML&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Hello everyone&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start and run apache&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;service httpd start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;head to your public ip address of your ec2 instance on your browser and you should be able to see the web server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-status-information&quot;&gt;Health Status Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom panel, on the tab &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Status Checks&lt;/code&gt;. It has the information about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;System Status Check&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Instance Status Check&lt;/code&gt;. 
&lt;strong&gt;System Status Check&lt;/strong&gt; : Check if aws is able to get network packets into the instance. If this status fails, theres probably a problem with the aws infrastructure.
&lt;strong&gt;Instance Status&lt;/strong&gt; : This check verifies if the instance’s operating system is accepting traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monitoring&quot;&gt;Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom panel, on the tab &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt;. You have system metrics which are updated every 5 minutes. You can enable detailed monitoring (which can cost a bit extra).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the different metrics here are accesible through cloud watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lab-summary&quot;&gt;Lab Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All newly created Instances have &lt;strong&gt;termination protection&lt;/strong&gt; turned off by default, you must turn it on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On an EBS-backed instance, the default action is for the root EBS volume to be &lt;strong&gt;deleted&lt;/strong&gt; when the instance is terminated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EBS Root Volumes of your &lt;strong&gt;DEFAULT AMI’s cannot be encrypted.&lt;/strong&gt; You can also use third party tool (such as bitlocker etc) to encrypt the root volume, or this can be done when creating AMI’s (lab to follow) in the AWS console or using the API.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional Volumes can be encrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EC2 101</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/05/31/EC2-101.html"/>
   <updated>2018-05-31T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/compute/2018/05/31/EC2-101</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-ec2&quot;&gt;What is EC2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A web service that provides resizable compute capacity in the cloud. AWS EC2 reduces the time required to obtain and boot a new server instances to minutes, allowing you to quickly scale capacity, both up and down, as your computing requirements change.
This has changed the economics of computing, by allowing you to pay only for what you actually use. EC2 provides developers the tools to build failure resilient applications and isolate themselves from common failure scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing-options&quot;&gt;Pricing Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;On Demand&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Allows you to pay a fixed rate by the hour ( or by the second ) with no commitment.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reserved&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Provides you with a capacity reservation, and offer a significant discount on the hourly charge for an instance. 1 Year to 3 Year contracts.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Spot&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;enables you to bid whatever price you want for instance capacity, providing for even greater savings if your applications have flexible start and end times.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dedicated Hosts&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Physical EC2 servers dedicated for your use. Dedicated Hosts can help you reduce costs by allowing you to use your existing server-bound software licenses.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-demand&quot;&gt;On Demand&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perfect for users that want the low cost and flexibility of AWS EC2 without any up-front payment or long-term commitment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications with short term, spiky, or unpredictable workloads that cannot be interrupted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications being developed or tested on Amazon EC2 for the first time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perfect for learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reserved-instances&quot;&gt;Reserved Instances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications with steady state or predicatable usage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications that require reserved capacity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users can make up-front payments to reduce their total computing costs, even further.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Standard Reserved Instances ( Up to 75% off on-demand price )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Convertible Reserved Instances ( Up to 54% off on-demand price ) feature the capability to change the attributes of the Reserved Instances as long as the exchange results in the creation of Reserved instances of equal or greater value.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scheduled Reserved Instances are available to launch within the time window you reserve. This option allows you to match your capacity reservation to a predictable recurring schedule that only requires a fraction of a day, a week, or a month.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spot-instances&quot;&gt;Spot Instances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications that have flexible start and end times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications that are only feasible at very low compute prices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users with an urgent need for the large amounts of additional computing capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dedicated-hosts&quot;&gt;Dedicated Hosts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Useful for regulatory requirements that may not support multitenant virtualization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great for licensing which does not support multi-tenancy or cloud deployments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be purchased On-Demand ( Paid hourly ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be purchased as a reservation for upto 70% off on the On-Demand price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ec2-instance-types&quot;&gt;EC2 Instance Types&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Family&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Speciality&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Use Case&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Field Programmable Gate Arrays&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Genomics research, financial analytics, realtime video processing, big data etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High Speed Storage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NoSQL DBs, Data Warehousing etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;G3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Graphics Intensive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Video Encoding, 3D Application Streaming.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;H1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High Disk Throughput&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MapReduce-based workloads, distributed file systems such as HDFS and MapR-FS.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low Cost, General Purpose&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Web servers / Small DB’s.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;D2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dense Storage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Fileservers / Data Warehousing / Hadoop&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;R4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Memory Optimized&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Memory Intensive Applications and Databases.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;M5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;General Purpose&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Application Servers.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;C5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Compute Optimized&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CPU Intensive Applications and Databases.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;P3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Graphics / Gerneral Purpose GPU&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Machine Learning, Bit Coin Mining etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;X1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Memory Optimized&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SAP HANA / Apache Spark etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FIGHT-DR-MCPX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ebs&quot;&gt;EBS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EC2 = Virtual Machine.
EBS = Virtual Disc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon EBS allows you to create storage volumes and attach them to EC2 instances. Once attached, you can create file system on top of these volumes, run a database, or use them in any other way you would use a block device. Amazon EBS volumes are placed in a specific &lt;em&gt;Availability Zone&lt;/em&gt;, where they are automatically replicated to protect you from the failure of a single component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ebs-volume-types&quot;&gt;EBS Volume Types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General Purpose SSD (GP2).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;General purpose, balances both price and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ratio of 3 IOPS per GB with upto 10,000 IOPS and the ability to burst up to 3000 IOPS for extended periods of time for volumes at 3334 GiB and above.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provisioned IOPS SSD (IO1).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Designed for I/O intensive applications such as large relational or NOSQL databases.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use if you need more than 10,000 IOPS.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can provision up to 20,000 IOPS per volume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Throughput Optimized HDD (ST1).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Big data.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data warehouses.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Log processing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cannot be a boot volume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cold HDD (SC1).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lowest Cost Storage for infrequently accessed workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;File Server.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cannot be a boot volume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magnetic (Standard).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lowest cost per gigabyte of all EBS volume types that is bootable. Magnetic volumes are ideal for workloads where data is accessed infrequently, and applications where the lowest storage cost is important.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ec2-exam-tips&quot;&gt;EC2 Exam tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EC2 Pricing Options
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If a spot instance is terminated by amazon ec2, you will not be charged for a partial hour of usage. However, if you terminate the instance yourself, &lt;strong&gt;you will be charged for the complete hour in which the instance ran.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EC2 Family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EBS Volume types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Welcome to AWS Developer Associate Notes</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/introduction/2018/05/30/welcome-aws-developer-associate-notes.html"/>
   <updated>2018-05-30T22:43:32+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/introduction/2018/05/30/welcome-aws-developer-associate-notes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;aws-developer-associate-notes&quot;&gt;AWS Developer Associate Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog will host all the notes that i will be taking as i go through the AWS Developer Associate Course on A Cloud Guru. I will be going through all the lectures and Labs. The main contents of the course are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;IAM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;EC2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;S3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Databases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;DynamoDB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Simple Queue Service ( SQS )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Simple Notification Service ( SNS )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Simple Workflow Service ( SWF )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Elastic Beanstalk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;CloudFormation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;AWS Shared Responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Route53 &amp;amp; DNS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;Virtual Private Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;The Exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all these topics are covered, i will take some of the simulated exams from their portal and attempt the real deal! Good luck to me!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>IAM</title>
   <link href="/sturdy-carnival/iam/2018/05/30/IAM.html"/>
   <updated>2018-05-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>/sturdy-carnival/iam/2018/05/30/IAM</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;identity-access-management-101&quot;&gt;Identity Access Management 101&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-iam&quot;&gt;What is IAM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An AWS service which is dedicated to manage users and fine tune their level of access to the AWS console. Mainly used for the administration and management of user access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-iam-give-you&quot;&gt;What does IAM give you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Centralised control of your AWS account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shared Access to your AWS account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Granular Permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identity Federation ( including active directory, facebook, linkedin etc ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multifactor Authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide temporary access for users/devices and services where necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows you to setup your own password rotation policy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrates with many different AWS services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support PCI DSS Compliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;critical-terms&quot;&gt;Critical Terms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User - End Users ( poeple )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Groups - A collection of users under one set of permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles - You create roles and assign them to AWS resources. ( ie EC2 instance )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policies - A document that defines one or more permissions ( can be attached to all 3 above )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-token-service--sts-&quot;&gt;Security Token Service ( STS )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grants users limited and temporary access to AWS resources. Users can come from three sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federation ( typically active directory )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Uses Security Assertion Markup Language ( SAML )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grants temporary access based off the users Active Directory Credentials. Does not need to be a user in IAM.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Single sign on allows users to log into AWS console without assigning IAM credentails.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federation with Mobile Apps
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use Facebook/Amazon/Google or other OpenID providers to login.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cross Account Access
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Let users from one AWS account access resources in another.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;understanding-key-terms&quot;&gt;Understanding Key Terms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Federation:&lt;/strong&gt; Combining or joining a list of users in one domain ( such as IAM ) with a list of users in another domain ( such as Active Directory, Facebook, etc )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Broker:&lt;/strong&gt; A service that allows you to take an identity from point A and join it ( &lt;em&gt;federate it&lt;/em&gt; ) to point B.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Store:&lt;/strong&gt; Services like Active Directory, Facebook, Google etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identities:&lt;/strong&gt; a user of a service like Facebook etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-answer-format&quot;&gt;Exam Answer Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;scenario-1&quot;&gt;Scenario 1&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop an Identity Broker to communicate with LDAP and AWS STS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identity Broker always authenticates with LDAP first, then with AWS STS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application then gets temporary access to AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;scenario-2&quot;&gt;Scenario 2&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop an Identity Broker to communicate with LDAP and AWS STS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identity Broker always authenticates with LDAP first, gets an IAM Role associated with the user.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application then authenticates with STS and assumes that IAM Role.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application uses that IAM role to interact with S3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;active-directory-federation&quot;&gt;Active Directory Federation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;authentication-via-active-directory-federation-service&quot;&gt;Authentication via Active Directory Federation Service&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob heads to the ADFS website to login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The login page authenticates Bob against Active Directory. Depending on the browser Bob may get prompted to enter his active directory credentials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob’s browser recieves a SAML assertion in the form of an authentication response from ADFS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob’s browser posts the SAML assertion to the AWS login endpoint for SAML.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Behind the scene the AssumeRoleWithSAML API is used to request temporary security credentials and then constructs a login URL to the AWS Management Console.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob’s browser recieves the login URL and is redirected to the console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From bobs perspective all he did was login to the AD portal and then redirected to the AWS management console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-identity-federation&quot;&gt;Web Identity Federation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;web-identity-federation-for-mobile-application&quot;&gt;Web Identity Federation for Mobile Application&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 1 - Authenticate with Identity Provider
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ie Facebook, Google, Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 2 - Obtain Temporary Security Credentials
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After obtaining an ID token, you can obtain temporary security credentials by making an AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity request.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 3 - Access AWS Resource
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ie list all the objects in the S3 bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;download objects from the S3 bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary-of-iam&quot;&gt;Summary of IAM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IAM consists of the following
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Users - have permissions to access AWS Resources&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Groups - which is a way to group the users and apply policies to them collectively.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Roles - a way to apply policies to have programatic access to AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Policy Documents - JSON defition of permissions to AWS resources which can be applied to Users, Groups and Roles.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IAM is universal, does not apply to regions as of yet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The root account is the account which is created during the AWS account setup. It has complete Admin access by default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New users have &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt; permissions when first created.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New users are assigned &lt;strong&gt;Access Key ID &amp;amp; Secret Access Keys&lt;/strong&gt; when first created.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;These are not the same as login credentials to login to AWS Management Console. This is only for the programatic access to the AWS resources via the AWS SDK / API’s and AWS Cli.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You only get to view these credentials &lt;strong&gt;(Access Key ID &amp;amp; Secret Access Keys)&lt;/strong&gt; only once, If you loose it has to be regenerated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always have to setup &lt;em&gt;Multifactor Authentication&lt;/em&gt; on the root account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can create and customise your own password rotation policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
