<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-06T18:58:02+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">AWS Developer Associate Notes</title><subtitle>Blog to keep track of what i have been studying for AWS Developer Associate Course. Also will be referrence to study before the exam.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">EC2 Security Groups</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-Security-Groups.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EC2 Security Groups" /><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-Security-Groups</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-Security-Groups.html">&lt;p&gt;A Security Group is a Virtual Firewall, which controls traffic in and out of your ec2 instance. Ec2 instances are launched with one or more security groups attached to it. Multiple security groups can be applied to one ec2 instance. This is also the first line of defence against any security threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any change to the security group or implementing rules across security groups, comes into effect immedietly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security groups are stateful, any rules added as inbound rules allows outbound rules.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are not able to deny any traffic, you can only allow traffic since all traffic is blocked by default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your ec2 instances will be able to communicate with each other if they have the default security group attached to them, regarless of the region they are based off of.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to attach more than one security group to an instance which is already running, go to actions-&amp;gt;Networking-&amp;gt;Change Security Groups-&amp;gt; and check all the security groups you want to attach for the instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All inbound traffic is blocked by default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All outbound traffic is allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes to security group takes effect immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can any number of EC2 instances within a security group.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can have multiple security groups attached to an instance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security groups are stateful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot block specific IP Addresses using security groups, instead use Network Access Control Lists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can specify allow rules, but not deny rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Eshan Shafeeq</name></author><category term="firewall" /><category term="security" /><category term="networking" /><category term="virtual firewall" /><summary type="html">A Security Group is a Virtual Firewall, which controls traffic in and out of your ec2 instance. Ec2 instances are launched with one or more security groups attached to it. Multiple security groups can be applied to one ec2 instance. This is also the first line of defence against any security threats.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EC2-EFS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EFS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EC2-EFS" /><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EFS</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EFS.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;elastic-file-system&quot;&gt;Elastic File System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aws elastic file system, is a storage service for EC2 instances. EFS is easy to use and provides a simple interface that allows users to create and configure file systems quickly and easily. With aws EFS, storage capacity is elastic, growing and shrinking automatically as you add and remove files so your applications have storage always when they need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supports the Network File System Version 4 (NFSv4) protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You only pay for the storage you use ( no pre-provisioning required ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can scale upto petabytes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can support thousands of concurrent NFS connections.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data is stored across multiple Availability Zones within a region.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read after Write consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block based storage, not object based storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-efs-volume&quot;&gt;Creating a EFS Volume&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way how it connects to EC2 instances is through your VPC. If you do not have any custom VPC’s you can connect them to the default VPC’s for the availability zones in your region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the VPC you want to connect the EFS to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the availability zones you want to assign them to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the availability zones, select the subnets you want them on, add the ip address you want it to have, and also attach the security groups for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the tags.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After reviewing it, Create the File System.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fantastic solution to have shared resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Eshan Shafeeq</name></author><category term="compute" /><category term="storage" /><summary type="html">Elastic File System</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EC2 EBS Volumes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EBS-Volumes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EC2 EBS Volumes" /><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EBS-Volumes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/05/EC2-EBS-Volumes.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;lab&quot;&gt;LAB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to aws services, and then goto EC2. One the left side panel, select Volumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The EBS volume and the EC2 instance has to be in the same availability zone, in order for the volume to be attached to the EC2 instance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All root volumes will have a snapshot id, which relates to the machine image its running.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There will be no down time when you modify your volumes, ( change the Hard disk type / change the disk size ). You may run into performance issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With standard volumes, you will not be able to modify the volumes. ( ST1 - pure magnetic )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to spin up an EC2 instance with the same volume in another availability zone:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Goto Actions and create a snapshot.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add the required information on the form and click create.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Goto snapshots.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Click on Actions and Select Create a Volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can select any volume type / volume size.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select any availability zone that you want.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And attach it to the EC2 instance you want.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create a snapshot of the EBS volume you would like to move to another EC2 instance, Create a volume from that snapshot.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can go to snapshots and copy the snapshot to any other region, if you want to switch region.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can create an image from that snapshot in order to boot from that volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots are normally used for backups, Where as Images are used to create new volumes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure when you create an image its an image of one volume, when you want to boot off from this image later on.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can also create AMI’s directly from the snapshots, and then move it to another region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Root Device is where the operating system is installed at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volumes-and-snapshots&quot;&gt;Volumes and Snapshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volumes exists on EBS
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Virtual Hard Disk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snapshots exist on S3.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When you go to S3, you will not be able to see any buckets with the snapshots in there.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots are copies of Volumes at a given time.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Taking the second snapshot would only save the state of the blocks that have been modified, and moved to S3.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Your first snapshot will take some time to create, after the first one it wont take that long anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To create a snapshot of a Volume which serve as a Root Volume, you should stop the running instance. But it is possible to take a snapshot of the running instance Root Volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can create AMI’s from both Volumes and Snapshots.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can change the EBS Volume sizes on the fly, including changing the size and storage type.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volumes will &lt;strong&gt;ALWAYS&lt;/strong&gt; be in the same availability zone as the EC2 Instance.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To move an EC2 volume from one Availability Zone/Region to another, take a snap or an image of it, then copy it to the new Availability Zone/Region.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Snapshots of encrypted volumes are encrypted automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volumes restored from encrypted snapshots are encrypted automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can share snapshots, but only if they are unecrypted.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;These snapshots can be shared with other aws accounts or it can be made completely public.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do this lab at least 3 times!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Eshan Shafeeq</name></author><category term="compute" /><category term="storage" /><summary type="html">LAB</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EC2-Lab-Summary</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/04/EC2-Lab-Summary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EC2-Lab-Summary" /><published>2018-06-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/04/EC2-Lab-Summary</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/06/04/EC2-Lab-Summary.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-an-ec2-instance&quot;&gt;Creating an EC2 Instance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select a region which you want your EC2 instance to be at.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Older regions will have most of the different types of EC2 instances available, newer ones will have less.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select an AMI right after clicking on “Launch Instance”.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You have many flavours of AMI’s available.
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Amazon Linux AMI&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Red Hat Enterprise Linux&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;SUSE Linux Enterprise Server&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Server 16.04 LTS&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Windows Server&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version numbers of the above will change new version get adapted.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Amazon linux AMI comes with all the required built in tools and SDK’s installed. (Free Tier Eligible)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose an Instance Type
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;t2.micro (Free Tier Eligible)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure Instance Details
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Main setup page for Ec2&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Under VPC you can select one of the subnets, there is one subnet for every single availability zone. &lt;strong&gt;You can never have one subnet that goes across multiple availability zones.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Selecting an IAM Role (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enable termination protection [ to prevent people from accidentally terminating the instance ]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Additional charges are applied for detailed monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Advanced details, you can pass in bootstrap scripts to automate tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add Storage
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select the required storage for the root volume.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;by default the &lt;strong&gt;root volume will be deleted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volume = virtual harddisk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the tags
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Help you to control costs.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Always do more than just name tags, drill down upto the department and staff id.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure Security Groups
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Its a virtual firewall&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Set the services you want to allow, [ ssh, http, https ]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can restrict services to only from your IP.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review everything and Launch
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create a keypair.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Either upload your own public key or create your keypair on the web interface and download.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hit launch instance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connect-to-the-running-instance&quot;&gt;Connect to the running Instance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use ssh to connect to your instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh ec2-user@[your_ec2_instance_public_ip-address] &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;your_keypair.pem]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once logged in, it maybe a good idea to update the AMI &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo yum update&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-web-server&quot;&gt;Creating a web server&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install apache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;yum &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;httpd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/var/www/html/&lt;/code&gt; and then add some &lt;em&gt;HTML&lt;/em&gt; in the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-HTML&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Hello everyone&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start and run apache&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;service httpd start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;head to your public ip address of your ec2 instance on your browser and you should be able to see the web server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-status-information&quot;&gt;Health Status Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom panel, on the tab &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Status Checks&lt;/code&gt;. It has the information about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;System Status Check&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Instance Status Check&lt;/code&gt;. 
&lt;strong&gt;System Status Check&lt;/strong&gt; : Check if aws is able to get network packets into the instance. If this status fails, theres probably a problem with the aws infrastructure.
&lt;strong&gt;Instance Status&lt;/strong&gt; : This check verifies if the instance’s operating system is accepting traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;monitoring&quot;&gt;Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom panel, on the tab &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt;. You have system metrics which are updated every 5 minutes. You can enable detailed monitoring (which can cost a bit extra).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the different metrics here are accesible through cloud watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lab-summary&quot;&gt;Lab Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All newly created Instances have &lt;strong&gt;termination protection&lt;/strong&gt; turned off by default, you must turn it on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On an EBS-backed instance, the default action is for the root EBS volume to be &lt;strong&gt;deleted&lt;/strong&gt; when the instance is terminated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EBS Root Volumes of your &lt;strong&gt;DEFAULT AMI’s cannot be encrypted.&lt;/strong&gt; You can also use third party tool (such as bitlocker etc) to encrypt the root volume, or this can be done when creating AMI’s (lab to follow) in the AWS console or using the API.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional Volumes can be encrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Eshan Shafeeq</name></author><category term="compute" /><category term="ec2" /><category term="virtual machine" /><category term="lab" /><summary type="html">Creating an EC2 Instance Select a region which you want your EC2 instance to be at. Older regions will have most of the different types of EC2 instances available, newer ones will have less. Select an AMI right after clicking on “Launch Instance”. You have many flavours of AMI’s available. Amazon Linux AMI Red Hat Enterprise Linux SUSE Linux Enterprise Server Ubuntu Server 16.04 LTS Microsoft Windows Server Version numbers of the above will change new version get adapted. Amazon linux AMI comes with all the required built in tools and SDK’s installed. (Free Tier Eligible) Choose an Instance Type t2.micro (Free Tier Eligible) Configure Instance Details Main setup page for Ec2 Under VPC you can select one of the subnets, there is one subnet for every single availability zone. You can never have one subnet that goes across multiple availability zones. Selecting an IAM Role (Optional) Enable termination protection [ to prevent people from accidentally terminating the instance ] Additional charges are applied for detailed monitoring. Advanced details, you can pass in bootstrap scripts to automate tasks. Add Storage Select the required storage for the root volume. by default the root volume will be deleted. Volume = virtual harddisk Set the tags Help you to control costs. Always do more than just name tags, drill down upto the department and staff id. Configure Security Groups Its a virtual firewall Set the services you want to allow, [ ssh, http, https ] You can restrict services to only from your IP. Review everything and Launch Create a keypair. Either upload your own public key or create your keypair on the web interface and download. Hit launch instance.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EC2 101</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/05/31/EC2-101.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EC2 101" /><published>2018-05-31T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-31T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/05/31/EC2-101</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compute/2018/05/31/EC2-101.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-ec2&quot;&gt;What is EC2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A web service that provides resizable compute capacity in the cloud. AWS EC2 reduces the time required to obtain and boot a new server instances to minutes, allowing you to quickly scale capacity, both up and down, as your computing requirements change.
This has changed the economics of computing, by allowing you to pay only for what you actually use. EC2 provides developers the tools to build failure resilient applications and isolate themselves from common failure scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pricing-options&quot;&gt;Pricing Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;On Demand&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Allows you to pay a fixed rate by the hour ( or by the second ) with no commitment.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reserved&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Provides you with a capacity reservation, and offer a significant discount on the hourly charge for an instance. 1 Year to 3 Year contracts.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Spot&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;enables you to bid whatever price you want for instance capacity, providing for even greater savings if your applications have flexible start and end times.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dedicated Hosts&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Physical EC2 servers dedicated for your use. Dedicated Hosts can help you reduce costs by allowing you to use your existing server-bound software licenses.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-demand&quot;&gt;On Demand&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perfect for users that want the low cost and flexibility of AWS EC2 without any up-front payment or long-term commitment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications with short term, spiky, or unpredictable workloads that cannot be interrupted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications being developed or tested on Amazon EC2 for the first time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perfect for learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reserved-instances&quot;&gt;Reserved Instances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications with steady state or predicatable usage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications that require reserved capacity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users can make up-front payments to reduce their total computing costs, even further.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Standard Reserved Instances ( Up to 75% off on-demand price )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Convertible Reserved Instances ( Up to 54% off on-demand price ) feature the capability to change the attributes of the Reserved Instances as long as the exchange results in the creation of Reserved instances of equal or greater value.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scheduled Reserved Instances are available to launch within the time window you reserve. This option allows you to match your capacity reservation to a predictable recurring schedule that only requires a fraction of a day, a week, or a month.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spot-instances&quot;&gt;Spot Instances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications that have flexible start and end times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applications that are only feasible at very low compute prices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users with an urgent need for the large amounts of additional computing capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dedicated-hosts&quot;&gt;Dedicated Hosts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Useful for regulatory requirements that may not support multitenant virtualization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great for licensing which does not support multi-tenancy or cloud deployments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be purchased On-Demand ( Paid hourly ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be purchased as a reservation for upto 70% off on the On-Demand price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ec2-instance-types&quot;&gt;EC2 Instance Types&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Family&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Speciality&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Use Case&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;F1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Field Programmable Gate Arrays&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Genomics research, financial analytics, realtime video processing, big data etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High Speed Storage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NoSQL DBs, Data Warehousing etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;G3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Graphics Intensive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Video Encoding, 3D Application Streaming.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;H1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High Disk Throughput&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MapReduce-based workloads, distributed file systems such as HDFS and MapR-FS.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low Cost, General Purpose&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Web servers / Small DB’s.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;D2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dense Storage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Fileservers / Data Warehousing / Hadoop&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;R4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Memory Optimized&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Memory Intensive Applications and Databases.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;M5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;General Purpose&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Application Servers.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;C5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Compute Optimized&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CPU Intensive Applications and Databases.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;P3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Graphics / Gerneral Purpose GPU&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Machine Learning, Bit Coin Mining etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;X1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Memory Optimized&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SAP HANA / Apache Spark etc.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FIGHT-DR-MCPX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ebs&quot;&gt;EBS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EC2 = Virtual Machine.
EBS = Virtual Disc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon EBS allows you to create storage volumes and attach them to EC2 instances. Once attached, you can create file system on top of these volumes, run a database, or use them in any other way you would use a block device. Amazon EBS volumes are placed in a specific &lt;em&gt;Availability Zone&lt;/em&gt;, where they are automatically replicated to protect you from the failure of a single component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ebs-volume-types&quot;&gt;EBS Volume Types&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General Purpose SSD (GP2).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;General purpose, balances both price and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ratio of 3 IOPS per GB with upto 10,000 IOPS and the ability to burst up to 3000 IOPS for extended periods of time for volumes at 3334 GiB and above.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provisioned IOPS SSD (IO1).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Designed for I/O intensive applications such as large relational or NOSQL databases.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use if you need more than 10,000 IOPS.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can provision up to 20,000 IOPS per volume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Throughput Optimized HDD (ST1).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Big data.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data warehouses.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Log processing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cannot be a boot volume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cold HDD (SC1).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lowest Cost Storage for infrequently accessed workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;File Server.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cannot be a boot volume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magnetic (Standard).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lowest cost per gigabyte of all EBS volume types that is bootable. Magnetic volumes are ideal for workloads where data is accessed infrequently, and applications where the lowest storage cost is important.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ec2-exam-tips&quot;&gt;EC2 Exam tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EC2 Pricing Options
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If a spot instance is terminated by amazon ec2, you will not be charged for a partial hour of usage. However, if you terminate the instance yourself, &lt;strong&gt;you will be charged for the complete hour in which the instance ran.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EC2 Family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EBS Volume types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Eshan Shafeeq</name></author><category term="compute," /><category term="virtualization," /><category term="cloud" /><summary type="html">What is EC2 A web service that provides resizable compute capacity in the cloud. AWS EC2 reduces the time required to obtain and boot a new server instances to minutes, allowing you to quickly scale capacity, both up and down, as your computing requirements change. This has changed the economics of computing, by allowing you to pay only for what you actually use. EC2 provides developers the tools to build failure resilient applications and isolate themselves from common failure scenarios.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to AWS Developer Associate Notes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/05/30/welcome-aws-developer-associate-notes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to AWS Developer Associate Notes" /><published>2018-05-30T22:43:32+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T22:43:32+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/05/30/welcome-aws-developer-associate-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/05/30/welcome-aws-developer-associate-notes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;aws-developer-associate-notes&quot;&gt;AWS Developer Associate Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog will host all the notes that i will be taking as i go through the AWS Developer Associate Course on A Cloud Guru. I will be going through all the lectures and Labs. The main contents of the course are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;IAM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;EC2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;S3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Databases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;DynamoDB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Simple Queue Service ( SQS )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Simple Notification Service ( SNS )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Simple Workflow Service ( SWF )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Elastic Beanstalk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;CloudFormation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;AWS Shared Responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Route53 &amp;amp; DNS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;Virtual Private Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; /&gt;The Exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all these topics are covered, i will take some of the simulated exams from their portal and attempt the real deal! Good luck to me!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">AWS Developer Associate Notes</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IAM</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/iam/2018/05/30/IAM.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IAM" /><published>2018-05-30T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/iam/2018/05/30/IAM</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/iam/2018/05/30/IAM.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;identity-access-management-101&quot;&gt;Identity Access Management 101&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-iam&quot;&gt;What is IAM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An AWS service which is dedicated to manage users and fine tune their level of access to the AWS console. Mainly used for the administration and management of user access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-iam-give-you&quot;&gt;What does IAM give you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Centralised control of your AWS account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shared Access to your AWS account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Granular Permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identity Federation ( including active directory, facebook, linkedin etc ).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multifactor Authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide temporary access for users/devices and services where necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows you to setup your own password rotation policy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrates with many different AWS services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support PCI DSS Compliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;critical-terms&quot;&gt;Critical Terms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User - End Users ( poeple )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Groups - A collection of users under one set of permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roles - You create roles and assign them to AWS resources. ( ie EC2 instance )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policies - A document that defines one or more permissions ( can be attached to all 3 above )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-token-service--sts-&quot;&gt;Security Token Service ( STS )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grants users limited and temporary access to AWS resources. Users can come from three sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federation ( typically active directory )
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Uses Security Assertion Markup Language ( SAML )&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grants temporary access based off the users Active Directory Credentials. Does not need to be a user in IAM.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Single sign on allows users to log into AWS console without assigning IAM credentails.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federation with Mobile Apps
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use Facebook/Amazon/Google or other OpenID providers to login.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cross Account Access
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Let users from one AWS account access resources in another.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;understanding-key-terms&quot;&gt;Understanding Key Terms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Federation:&lt;/strong&gt; Combining or joining a list of users in one domain ( such as IAM ) with a list of users in another domain ( such as Active Directory, Facebook, etc )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Broker:&lt;/strong&gt; A service that allows you to take an identity from point A and join it ( &lt;em&gt;federate it&lt;/em&gt; ) to point B.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Store:&lt;/strong&gt; Services like Active Directory, Facebook, Google etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identities:&lt;/strong&gt; a user of a service like Facebook etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exam-answer-format&quot;&gt;Exam Answer Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;scenario-1&quot;&gt;Scenario 1&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop an Identity Broker to communicate with LDAP and AWS STS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identity Broker always authenticates with LDAP first, then with AWS STS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application then gets temporary access to AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;scenario-2&quot;&gt;Scenario 2&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop an Identity Broker to communicate with LDAP and AWS STS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identity Broker always authenticates with LDAP first, gets an IAM Role associated with the user.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application then authenticates with STS and assumes that IAM Role.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application uses that IAM role to interact with S3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;active-directory-federation&quot;&gt;Active Directory Federation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;authentication-via-active-directory-federation-service&quot;&gt;Authentication via Active Directory Federation Service&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob heads to the ADFS website to login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The login page authenticates Bob against Active Directory. Depending on the browser Bob may get prompted to enter his active directory credentials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob’s browser recieves a SAML assertion in the form of an authentication response from ADFS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob’s browser posts the SAML assertion to the AWS login endpoint for SAML.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Behind the scene the AssumeRoleWithSAML API is used to request temporary security credentials and then constructs a login URL to the AWS Management Console.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bob’s browser recieves the login URL and is redirected to the console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From bobs perspective all he did was login to the AD portal and then redirected to the AWS management console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-identity-federation&quot;&gt;Web Identity Federation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;web-identity-federation-for-mobile-application&quot;&gt;Web Identity Federation for Mobile Application&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 1 - Authenticate with Identity Provider
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ie Facebook, Google, Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 2 - Obtain Temporary Security Credentials
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After obtaining an ID token, you can obtain temporary security credentials by making an AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity request.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 3 - Access AWS Resource
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ie list all the objects in the S3 bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;download objects from the S3 bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary-of-iam&quot;&gt;Summary of IAM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IAM consists of the following
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Users - have permissions to access AWS Resources&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Groups - which is a way to group the users and apply policies to them collectively.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Roles - a way to apply policies to have programatic access to AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Policy Documents - JSON defition of permissions to AWS resources which can be applied to Users, Groups and Roles.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IAM is universal, does not apply to regions as of yet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The root account is the account which is created during the AWS account setup. It has complete Admin access by default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New users have &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt; permissions when first created.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New users are assigned &lt;strong&gt;Access Key ID &amp;amp; Secret Access Keys&lt;/strong&gt; when first created.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;These are not the same as login credentials to login to AWS Management Console. This is only for the programatic access to the AWS resources via the AWS SDK / API’s and AWS Cli.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You only get to view these credentials &lt;strong&gt;(Access Key ID &amp;amp; Secret Access Keys)&lt;/strong&gt; only once, If you loose it has to be regenerated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always have to setup &lt;em&gt;Multifactor Authentication&lt;/em&gt; on the root account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can create and customise your own password rotation policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Eshan Shafeeq</name></author><category term="accounts," /><category term="management," /><category term="access" /><category term="control," /><category term="security," /><category term="authorization" /><summary type="html">Identity Access Management 101</summary></entry></feed>